Hmmm.
うーん。
Music
音楽
All right,
わかった、
join me and clear the thank you for the
私と一緒に、ありがとうをクリアしてください
Introduce Academia Sinica to participate
参加する中央研究院を紹介する
Our presentation for today's Feast of Knowledge
今日の知識の饗宴のプレゼンテーション
I'm here to represent the Central Court
私は中央裁判所を代表してここに来ました
Introducing our speakers today
本日のスピーカーのご紹介
Today's speaker is Professor Cai Dingping
今日の講演者は蔡鼎平教授です。
Currently in Academia Sinica
現在現任中研院
Director of Applied Science Research Center
応用科学研究センター長
Special Review Researcher
特別審査研究員
He is also a special commentary professor at the Department of Physics, National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学物理学科の特別解説教授でもある
Some of the information you have is very detailed.
あなたが持っている情報の中には、非常に詳細なものもあります。
Introduction to Professor Cai
蔡教授の紹介
I just need to pick a few points
いくつかのポイントをピックアップする必要があるだけです
He is now the chairman of the Taiwan Information Storage Association
彼は現在、台湾情報ストレージ協会の会長を務めています。
Chairman of the Optoelectronic Society of the Republic of China
中華民国光電子学会会長
It is also a meeting of the American Physical Society in Taiwan
台湾でのアメリカ物理学会の会合でもあります
Meetings of the International Society for Electrical and Electronic Engineering
国際電気電子学会の会合
Meetings of the Optical Society of America
アメリカ光学学会の会合
International Optoelectronic Society
国際光電子学会
Meetings of the Society of Engineering
工学学会の集会
Meeting of the Academy of Electromagnetic Sciences
電磁科学アカデミーの会議
There is also a meeting of the Asia Pacific Academy of Materials Sciences
アジア太平洋材料科学アカデミーの会合もあります
And finally, the meeting of the Physical Society of the Republic of China
そして最後に中華民国物理学会の総会
So his academic achievement is very high
だから彼の学業成績は非常に高い
Then published more than two hundred papers
その後200以上の論文を発表
book or other that chapter
本やその他のその章
A total of forty-nine conference papers
合計 49 件の会議資料
Thirty-nine other technical reports and other papers
その他の技術レポートおよびその他の論文 39 件
There are 41 domestic and foreign patents
国内外の特許は41件あります
So the academic achievement is very high
なので学業成績も非常に高いです
has won many awards
多くの賞を受賞しています
I just cite a few of the most important ones
最も重要なものをいくつか引用します
National Science Council's Fifty Scientific Achievement Awards
米国科学会議の 50 の科学功績賞
There is also the Industry-University Cooperation Award from the Ministry of Education
文科省産学連携賞も受賞
the main thing is
主なことは
NSC Contact Research Award twice
NSCコンタクト研究賞2回
and academic awards from the Ministry of Education
文部省からの学術賞など
it's very rare
とても珍しいです
Foundation Research Contact Awards and more
財団研究連絡賞など
The topic he is talking to us today is
今日彼が私たちに話しているテーマは
Very relevant to his research is the
彼の研究に非常に関連しているのは、
About Photon New Era
Photon New Eraについて
because we know that in 2015
2015年にはそれがわかっているから
Last year was an International Year of Light
昨年は国際光年でした
Specially designate this year as the Year of Light
今年を光の年として特別に指定する
It's because I want to attract everyone
みんなを魅了したいから
Focus on so-called photonics
いわゆるフォトニクスに焦点を当てる
light-based technology
光ベースの技術
in this new era
この新しい時代に
In this new century of ours
私たちのこの新しい世紀に
Lots of new camp fun going on
新しいキャンプの楽しみがたくさん始まります
useful some development
役に立つ開発
This is the topic he mainly introduced to us today.
これが今日彼が私たちに主に紹介したトピックです。
Chinese is called Photon New Era
中国語はPhoton New Eraと呼ばれます
English is Photonics for the New Era
英語は新しい時代のフォトニクスです
So I thought my introduction
それで私は私の自己紹介を考えました
not too long
長すぎません
everyone can save time
誰もが時間を節約できる
Let's listen to Director Cai's wonderful speech
蔡局長の素晴らしいスピーチを聞いてみましょう
thank you all we have now applauded
皆さん、今拍手を送りました、ありがとうございます
welcome to our chair today
今日は私たちの椅子にようこそ
good night everybody
おやすみ皆さん
It is a great honor to have this opportunity today
本日はこのような機会を頂き大変光栄です
Come to this today's
今日はこれに来てください
very important report
とても重要な報告
I will give you a brief report
簡単にご報告させていただきます
Thanks also to my colleagues
同僚にも感謝します
they helped me choose
彼らは私が選ぶのを手伝ってくれました
Fortunix for the New Era
新時代のフォーチュニクス
title of this speech
このスピーチのタイトル
I feel very honored
とても光栄に思います
in the first chamber of the house of representatives
下院第一議場で
inside give such a report
中でそのような報告をします
Coming to the House of Representatives is already fast
衆議院に来るのはもう早いです
just over four years passed
4年余りが過ぎた
Learned a lot in the past four years
この4年間でたくさんのことを学びました
There are many very, very good and outstanding seniors, experts and scholars in the Chinese language
中国語の非常に優れた優れた先輩、専門家、学者がたくさんいます。
so if there's anything wrong with my report today
それで、今日の私の報告に何か間違っているところがあれば
Ken please correct me a lot
ケン、たくさん訂正してください
Then my report today is roughly divided into two parts.
それでは、本日の私の報告は大きく二つに分かれております。
In the first part, let me briefly tell you
前半で簡単に説明させていただきますと、
A short story about the 2015 International Year of Light in Taiwan
台湾の 2015 年国際光年に関する短編小説
about ten minutes
約10分
Then I will report to you some recent stories about optics
それでは、光学に関する最近の話をいくつかご報告します。
That's because a colleague specifically told me
それは同僚が私に具体的に言ったからです
This talk is not an academic talk is this knowledge sharing
この講演は学術的な講演ではなく、知識の共有です
So it must be maintained without the formula
したがって、公式なしで維持する必要があります
then tell the story
それから話をしてください
This is very difficult for me
これは私にとってとても難しいことです
because you cut pork every day
毎日豚肉を切るから
Suddenly today came a handful of vegetables for you to cut
今日突然、あなたが切るための野菜がいくつか届きました
that's weird
それは変だ
So I started preparing for this talk this morning
それで私は今朝この講演の準備を始めました
ready to just
ちょうど準備ができて
so sorry
ごめんなさい
If there is something incomplete, please advise
不備な点がございましたらご相談ください
The Year of Light 2015
2015 年光の年
Basically because of the past few years
基本的にここ数年のせいで
I have been back to Taiwan for more than 20 years
台湾に戻って20年以上になります
this continuous learning
この継続的な学習
continuous efforts
継続的な努力
I have always believed that science is the way of the old country
私は科学が古い国のやり方だといつも信じてきました
It is also the way of the new country
それは新しい国のやり方でもある
but over the years
しかし、何年にもわたって
Not only are there things in the courtyard
中庭で何かが起こっているだけではありません
There are many other foreign things outside the hospital
病院の外には他にも異物がたくさんあります
On the contrary, many important things
逆に大切なことはたくさんある
That's why I want to say that I still use such precious time
だから今も貴重な時間を使ってるって言いたい
Tell everyone the ins and outs of this whole story
この物語の一部始終をみんなに伝えてください
Because a lot of people don't know
知らない人も多いので
But in fact, this is a very large event that takes place around the world.
しかし実際には、これは世界中で行われる非常に大きなイベントです。
First of all, I would like to thank Chen Boru, a student from Jiangdong University
まず最初に、江東大学の学生、チェン・ボルさんに感謝したいと思います。
There is also a dub that puts this
これを入れたダブもあります
A short video of a whole world to share with you
あなたと共有するための全世界の短いビデオ
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Light allows us to see what Chie Yue imagined
光によって、Chie Yue が想像したものを見ることができます
Light will drive the economy of the future
光が未来の経済を動かす
Light enables us to reduce disease and treat disease
光は病気の軽減と治療を可能にします
Light guards our society
光は私たちの社会を守る
Light will be the key to solving the most expensive problems of the mind
光は心の最も高価な問題を解決する鍵となるでしょう
When the light fades and disappears on Dali
ダリの光が消えてゆくとき
our day will be over
私たちの一日は終わります
And our future will shine and keep turning
そして僕らの未来は輝いて回り続ける
Thanks
ありがとう
last shot elected one
最後のショットが選ばれたもの
The last shot was actually selected as an image of a very important promotion in the world
最後のショットは実際に世界的に非常に重要なプロモーションの画像として選ばれました
That image is a little girl
そのイメージは小さな女の子です
Not just now that girl has a picture
その女の子が写真を持っているのは今だけではありません
is a little girl
小さな女の子です
lying on a wooden floor
木の床に横たわって
Then there is an LED light that costs less than one dollar next to it
その隣には1ドル以下のLEDライトがあります
that was in south america
それは南アメリカでした
a very poor remote country
とても貧しい辺境の国
places without electricity
電気のない場所
children in
の子供たち
afternoon
午後
After assisting parents Luo Blind
両親のルオ・ブラインドを支援した後
back home
家に帰って
Then use the Une
次に、Une を使用します。
LED light provided
LEDライト付属
lying on the floor to write his day's
床に寝転がって一日のことを書く
home work
家庭作業
those are
それらは
united nations humanitarian organization
国連人道支援機関
The United Nations Culture and Education is the institution of UNEASYS
国連文化教育はUNEASYSの機関です
to help remote countries
遠く離れた国を助けるために
In fact, in 2013, this activity has already been promoted by Promote
実はこの活動は2013年にすでにプロモート社によって推進されています。
That's when UNESCO declared 2015 to be the International Year of Light
ユネスコが2015年を国際光年と宣言したのはその時だった
So why the International Year of Light?
では、なぜ国際光年なのでしょうか？
Because in fact in 2005
というのも、実は2005年に
Do you still remember the year when Building 101 was just completed?
101号館が完成したばかりの年のことをまだ覚えていますか?
None of his offices are rented out
彼のオフィスはどこも貸していない
Then the window later has an E equal to MC squared
その後、ウィンドウの E は MC の 2 乗に等しくなります。
Celebrating the Year of Physics
物理年を祝う
2015 is the year of light
2015年は光の年です
There is also a chemical year and an astronomical year in between
間には化学年と天文年もあります
why?
なぜ？
The reason, of course, is that light is a very important
その理由はもちろん、光が非常に重要だからです。
is an important element of human civilization
人類文明の重要な要素
an important element in the origin of life
生命の起源に関わる重要な要素
Arguments are currently important in medicine, communication, economy, environment, society, and culture
議論は現在、医学、コミュニケーション、経済、環境、社会、文化において重要です
So it was decided to have a light year
それで光年を持つことが決定されました
85 UNESCO members from all over the world participated
世界中から85人のユネスコ会員が参加
Although we are not, we in Taiwan also participated in this event
ではありませんが、台湾の私たちもこのイベントに参加しました
This event is a global event
このイベントは世界規模のイベントです
Why do you want to promote this matter?
なぜこの件を推進したいのですか？
It is because human civilization, whether in science and technology, or in nature and culture
それは、科学技術であろうと、自然や文化であろうと、人類の文明だからです。
Light actually played a very important role.
実は光はとても重要な役割を果たしています。
Needless to say, many people know about this
言うまでもなく、多くの人がこのことを知っています
but ignored it
しかし無視した
Because Laozi said that elephants have no form
老子は象には形がないと言っているから
It's just that many people take it granted
つまり、多くの人がそれを当然だと思っている
That is to say, take it for granted, as if the light turns on when you press your hand
つまり、手を押すとライトが点灯するように、それを当たり前のこととして受け止めてください。
Well, a lot of things are not like that
多くのことはそうではない
in many places around the world
世界中の多くの場所で
Human civilization still has a different aspect
人類の文明にはまだ異なる側面がある
This year of light has a LOGO
今年の光の年にはロゴが入りました
It is the light source representing the sun
太陽を表す光源です
origin perpetual culture very long
非常に長い起源の永続的な文化
There are also representatives of various international countries and races
さまざまな国や人種の代表者もいます
There is also a sense of tolerance
包容力もあります
Then different colors represent different races
そして、異なる色は異なる人種を表します
Spectrum also represents the diversity of science, art, culture, education, etc.
スペクトルは科学、芸術、文化、教育などの多様性も表します。
Diversified one LOGO
多様な1つのロゴ
I have prepared ten badges for each
バッジを10個ずつ用意しました
I'll send it to you later
後で送ります
There are two kinds here, there are twenty
ここには2種類あり、20個あります
One is the badge made by the International Society for Optoelectronic Engineering
1 つは国際光電子工学学会が作成したバッジです。
The other one is Taiwan Fotonic Society
もう一つは台湾フォトニック協会です
made badge
作ったバッジ
that was made by
それはによって作られました
Vice Chairman Sun Qingcheng designed it
孫清成副会長が設計した
There is a jade mountain at the bottom
麓には翡翠の山がある
Then the above LOGO is exactly the same
すると上のロゴは全く同じです
Wait a minute, if you are interested, you can come and get it
ちょっと待って、興味があれば取​​りに来てください
In addition to that
それに加えて
Why choose 2015
2015 を選ぶ理由
The reason is because of many important developments
その理由は、多くの重要な進展があるためです
like this 1965 50 years ago
こんな感じ 50年前の1965年
Gao Kun and the others developed this optical fiber technology
Gao Kunらが開発した光ファイバー技術
then 1915
その後1915年
special relativity
特殊相対性理論
general relativity
一般相対性理論
Estan's general theory of relativity
エスタンの一般相対性理論
then 1865
その後1865年
Just happens to be Max Ware
たまたまマックス・ウェアだった
He took all the physical properties of this light
彼はこの光のすべての物理的特性を取得しました
explained in terms of electromagnetic waves
電磁波で説明すると
that 1815
その1815年
Fernand believes that light has the property of fluctuations
フェルナンは、光には変動の性質があると信じています。
And then, 2015 is the year Western Civilization decides for the first time that humans understand what light is
そして2015年は、西洋文明が人類が光とは何かを初めて理解したと判断した年となる
There is the first book on light
光に関する最初の本が出版される
What about this one haytham , an arab
アラブ人のヘイザムはどうですか？
He was originally an intellectual, working for the Emperor
彼はもともと天皇に仕えた知識人でした。
Then, later, he was imprisoned in prison for minor incidents
その後、彼は軽微な事件で刑務所に投獄されました
He is in prison, there is nothing to do
彼は刑務所にいる、何もすることがない
Because I am usually very busy, I have to prepare Powerpoint and speeches
私は普段とても忙しいので、パワーポイントやスピーチの準備をしなければなりません
There's nothing to do in prison
刑務所では何もすることがない
He began to notice that from sunrise to sunset, he looked at the fence of the cell
彼は日の出から日没まで独房の柵を見ていることに気づき始めた
He discovered that light is a diameter, and then the shadow of light is like a straight line
彼は、光は直径であり、光の影は直線のようであることを発見しました。
So, he wrote down some very basic principles of optics
そこで、彼は光学の非常に基本的な原理をいくつか書き留めました。
For example, say light is of diameter
たとえば、光に直径があるとします。
The angle of this projection of light is relevant
この光の投影の角度が重要です
He wrote some very basic concepts of geometric optics
彼は幾何光学の非常に基本的な概念をいくつか書きました
The origin of books that were then identified as optics by Western civilization
当時西洋文明によって光学として認識された本の起源
But here are Mozi, Shenggua and Li Shizhen
しかし、ここにはMozi、Shenggua、Li Shizhenがいます
In fact, Mozi was 2500 years ago
実際、墨子は2500年前のものでした。
This one specifically writes some very important descriptions of optics.
これは光学に関する非常に重要な説明を具体的に書いています。
That was also 3000 years ago in this year 1945
それも3000年前の1945年のこと
This in this 1945 in this prince's tomb in this Shanmen Gorge
これは 1945 年にこの山門渓谷にある太子の墓で
This is the discovery of the Western State's foreign tax
これは西部州の外国税の発見です
That foreign tax is one
その外国税もその一つです
This concave copper mirror
この凹面銅鏡
It can actually be used to dry some
実際に乾燥させるのにも使えます
love grass or dried leaves
草や枯れ葉が大好き
can be ignited
点火できる
It's kind of like a lighter now
今ではライターのようなものです
that is to pick up
それは拾うことです
Beat Lai and smoke a cigarette
ライを倒してタバコを吸う
or some incense
またはお香
Then this is such a thing
じゃあ、こういう事なんですね
and it's done really well
そしてそれは本当に良い仕事をします
very well done
非常によくやりました
So the rep said
そこで担当者はこう言いました
These technologies have actually been around for a long time.
これらのテクノロジーは実際には長い間存在していました。
Then in Needham's history of Chinese science and technology
次にニーダムの中国科学技術史
I mentioned Mozi about
私はモジについて言及しました
Optics Research Vs
光学研究 vs.
known greece as early as
ギリシャでは早くから知られていた
earlier than India and Arabia
インドやアラビアよりも早い
Because Mozi was from 2500 years ago
墨子は2500年前の人だから
So in Mokin he has drawings
つまり、モーキンには絵が描かれています
that picture means
その絵が意味するのは、
through a small hole
小さな穴を通して
This image is upside down
この画像は上下逆さまです
That's all evidence
それがすべての証拠です
not made up
でっち上げられていない
so here
それでここで
include
含む
Imaging with pinholes, including concave-convex mirror imaging
ピンホールを利用したイメージング（凹凸ミラーイメージングを含む）
Imaging including combined mirrors
複合ミラーを含むイメージング
In fact, two or three thousand years ago
実は二、三千年前に
Humans have probably recorded
おそらく人間が記録したのでしょう
and know these things
そしてこれらのことを知ってください
that's a pity
それは残念だ
That is to say, the optics textbooks we read
つまり、私たちが読む光学の教科書は、
I study optics
私は光学を勉強しています
so no mention of these things
したがって、これらのことについては言及しません
do not know either
どちらも知りません
Now everyone thinks that this optical
今では誰もがこの光学式だと考えています
The very important reason is because
非常に重要な理由は、
it is the origin of life
それは生命の根源です
It is more important to keep in good health than everyone now
今は誰よりも健康を保つことが大切です
Very related to this Healthcare
このヘルスケアに非常に関連しています
and everyone knows
そして誰もが知っています
The mobile phones you are using now
あなたが今使っている携帯電話
In fact, when you pick up your mobile phone, it is transmitted to the base station.
実際、携帯電話を手に取ると、それが基地局に送信されます。
The base station is directly connected to the aperture of the sewer
基地局は下水道の開口部に直結
Then the aperture helps you run the longest distance
絞りは最長距離を走るのに役立ちます
Then the shortest way is actually to the base station
そうすると実際には基地局に行くのが最短距離です
So this communication of light
つまりこの光のコミュニケーションは
In fact, it is to allow human civilization to have the so-called private message phone
実際、それは人類文明がいわゆるプライベートメッセージ電話を持つことを可能にすることです
The only way to have so-called various means of communication
いわゆる様々な通信手段を持つ唯一の方法
In addition, many optical instruments and cosmic hot cables
さらに、多くの光学機器や宇宙ホットケーブル
Launch many artificial satellites from now on
これからたくさんの人工衛星を打ち上げてください
Many devices to explore the universe
宇宙を探索するためのさまざまな装置
are actually optical devices
実は光学デバイスです
So optical activities are actually very important in science
つまり、光学活性は科学において実際に非常に重要です
on culture
文化について
also in education
教育においても
still in nature
まだ自然の中に
and art
そして芸術
It's actually quite important
実はかなり重要なことなんです
I won't go back one by one
いちいち戻らないよ
because time is limited
時間は限られているので
In the last slide, this part is about the design of light and shadow in general
最後のスライドでは、光と影のデザイン全般について説明します。
And the lighting in your home
そしてあなたの家の照明も
And the way these lights of the road project
道路の灯りがどのように投影されるか
Course Study Astronomy Universe
コース研究 天文学の宇宙
beautiful starry sky
美しい星空
I haven't seen the real Xinxin for a long time
本当のシンシンを長い間見ていない
Because there is a lot of light pollution in the city
市内は光害が多いので
Actually light is a very, very important thing
実は光ってとてもとても大切なものなんです
For the environment
環境のために
I'll explain more later
後ほど詳しく説明します
The bottom two are archaeological
下の2つは考古学的なものです
this is in mexico with leda
ここはレダと一緒にメキシコにいます
It's a radar made of lasers
レーザーでできたレーダーです
Do some scans of some old ruins
いくつかの古い遺跡をスキャンしてください
After scanning, there are some remains of pyramids
スキャン後、ピラミッドの残骸がいくつかあります
Actually it's not very significant now
実は今はそれほど重要ではない
because after a long time
長い時間が経ってから
It's all covered with dust
全部埃まみれだよ
But if you detect it optically
しかし光学的に検出すると
you can actually find
実際に見つけることができます
Some are already weathered
すでに風化しているものもある
or thousands of years later
あるいは数千年後
have turned into ruins like mud
泥のような廃墟と化した
So in fact optical technology
つまり実際には光学技術
It is very, very important to the development of human civilization
それは人類文明の発展にとって非常に重要です
OK, so this one was in 2015
OK、これは2015年のものです
Covers of various magazines and periodicals
各種雑誌や定期刊行物の表紙
It's all about light
すべては光についてです
In the end, some people even used optical communication
最後には光通信を使う人もいた
Look at Europe is 27.8TB per second
ヨーロッパを見ると毎秒 27.8TB
That is, 27.8 TB of bits are transferred in one second
つまり、1 秒間に 27.8 TB のビットが転送されることになります。
But in Africa it's actually only 397Gb
しかしアフリカでは実際には 397Gb しかありません
If this difference is made, the transmission speed will be nearly five or six hundred times worse.
この差が生じると、通信速度は 500 ～ 600 倍近く悪くなります。
So it can be seen that the civilizations of various regions
したがって、さまざまな地域の文明が
In fact, it is closely related to optical communication or optical development.
実は光通信や光開発と密接な関係があります。
So if we define the development of civilization on this earth by this
したがって、この地球上の文明の発展をこれで定義すると、
in fact a way
実際にはある方法で
then say otherwise
それなら違うと言う
Because the optical industry is called Fotonics Industry
光学産業はフォトニクス産業と呼ばれているため
Fotonics are photons
フォトニクスは光子です
Fotonics is the research knowledge of photons
フォトニクスは光子の研究知識です
This field includes LED lighting
この分野にはLED照明が含まれます
Including image sensing
画像センシングも含めて
Communications including fiber optics
光ファイバーを含む通信
including precision optics
精密光学部品を含む
Light sources including lasers
レーザーを含む光源
including optical storage
光学式ストレージを含む
Includes flat display
フラットディスプレイを搭載
There is also an optical assist device
光学補助装置もある
What is an optical auxiliary device
光補助装置とは
Optical auxiliary device is to convert photons into electrons
光補助装置は光子を電子に変換するものです
Then it becomes energy that can be used by human beings
そして人間が使えるエネルギーになるのです
Devices like solar cells
太陽電池などのデバイス
good
良い
These areas have undergone major developments in human civilization
これらの地域は人類の文明において大きな発展を遂げてきました。
There are also very significant developments in Taiwan
台湾でも非常に重要な進展が見られる
Taiwan since 1996
1996年から台湾
industries with such optics
このような光学機器を使用する産業
the optical industry
光学産業
Improve every year
毎年改善
then you will ask me
それならあなたは私に尋ねます
What is the approximate amount of this industry?
この業界のおおよその金額はいくらですか?
You can take a look
見てみることができます
It is in the field of the nine items just now
先ほど9項目の欄にあります
How many products we sell each year
年間に販売する製品の数
It can be seen here
ここで見ることができます
billions of billions each
それぞれ何十億も
$80 billion
800億美金
That's 80 billion US dollars
それは800億米ドルです
We sell in Taiwan
台湾でも売ってます
These optoelectronic related industries
これらの光エレクトロニクス関連産業
$80 billion
800億美金
What is the largest of the 80 billion US dollars?
800億米ドルのうち最大のものはいくらですか?
it is this
これです
This is the Fed Panel Display
これはFRBのパネルディスプレイです
flat panel display
フラットパネルディスプレイ
So this flat-panel display probably grew more than half of its output value
したがって、このフラットパネルディスプレイは、おそらくその出力値の半分以上成長したことになります。
so in fact
だから実際のところ
Taiwan is actually in the world
台湾は実は世界にある
Play an important role
重要な役割を果たす
Because the global market is
なぜなら、世界市場は、
Write 80 billion here
ここに800億と書いてください
The global market is about 20 times bigger than ours
世界市場は私たちの市場の約20倍です
so we take 5 percent
したがって 5 パーセントを受け取ります
we account for 5 percent
私たちは5パーセントを占めています
So the entire key market
したがって、主要市場全体が
It is very important to Taiwan's people's livelihood technology
台湾の人々の生活技術にとって非常に重要です
employment, industrial development, scientific development of the country
国の雇用、産業の発展、科学の発展
is very important
はとても重要です
So the Key Society of the Republic of China
したがって、中華民国の主要な協会は、
United Nations Cultural Organization
国連文化機関
There is also the cooperation of the International Wannian Engineering Society
国際万年工学協会の協力もあります
promote this event
このイベントを宣伝する
Activities in Taiwan
台湾での活動
Specially invited other relevant
その他関係者を特別招待
像TISA、TVA、TVS、TOSA
画像TISA、TVA、TVS、TOSA
and the Physical Society of the Republic of China
および中華民国物理学会
Optoelectronic Society of the Republic of China
中華民国光電子学会
These participate in an event like this
このようなイベントに参加する人たち
This activity is actually
実はこのイベント、
In August 2014 we
2014 年 8 月に私たちは
Special invitation to Vice Chairman Sun Qingcheng
孫清成副会長への特別招待
Director of the Institute of Optoelectronics, Chuo University
中央大学光エレクトロニクス研究所長
to represent us
私たちを代表して
Then in this December of 2014
そして、この 2014 年の 12 月に
we have a very important
私たちにはとても重要なことがあります
an opening ceremony
一個opening ceremony
Also invited this Mr. Zhang Zhou
張周氏も招待
and the International Society for Optoelectronic Engineering in the United States
および米国光電子工学協会
CEO and Swedish
CEOとスウェーデン人
Head of the Royal Academy Physics Group
ロイヤル・アカデミー物理学グループ長
And there is our Academician Reid Cai
そして私たちのアカデミー会員、リード・カイがいます
participated in such an event together
そんなイベントに一緒に参加しました
This is Academician Reid
こちらは学者リードです
This is Zhang Zhou
張周です
This is the CEO of SPIE
SPIEのCEOです
This is the chairman of Taiwan Optical Industry Federation
こちらは台湾光学産業連合会の会長です
We also have a lot of activities
アクティビティも豊富です
I should not meet
会わなければいいのに
The first prize is to show you these activities
一等賞はこれらの活動を紹介することです
In various universities, various events to vent the beauty of light have also been held.
光の美しさを伝えるために、さまざまな大学でもさまざまなイベントが開催されています
Or the official program is at the Institute of Optoelectronics, National Taiwan University
または、正式なプログラムは国立台湾大学光電子研究所にあります。
Hosted by Principal Yang
楊校長が主催
We also invited Dr. Shi Dacheng, chairman of the Optoelectronics Technology Industry Association, to give a speech
また、オプトエレクトロニクス技術産業協会会長の石大成博士を講演に招待しました。
Then, Professor Sun Qingheng was also sent to participate in the important activities of global RIL in Paris, France
その後、孫清恒教授もフランスのパリでの世界的なRILの重要な活動に参加するために派遣されました。
It's the United Nations Organization for Science and Technology to participate in this conference
この会議に参加するのは国連科学技術機関です
National Synchronization Assistance Center in this childhood Hsinchu, Taiwan
幼少期の台湾・新竹にある国家同期支援センター
Director Guoshang also specially held the inauguration ceremony of Taiwan Photon Park
郭尚所長は台湾フォトンパークの落成式も特別に執り行った
It has become a very important event for Taiwan in the international arena
国際舞台において台湾にとって非常に重要なイベントとなっている
very big highlight
非常に大きなハイライト
Of course, there are various activities in this planetarium.
もちろん、このプラネタリウムではさまざまなアクティビティがあります。
Including the lamp there will be an exhibition of Einstein's main lamp
ランプをはじめ、アインシュタインのメインランプも展示します
Chairman of the Japanese Society of Government Studies of OSJ in Japan
日本OSJ日本政府学会会長
President of SPIE's International Conceptual Engineering Society
SPIE 国際概念工学協会会長
The chairman of the Taiwan Government-Academia Trade Union was also present.
台湾官学労働組合の委員長も同席した。
Our event is in fact an international event
私たちのイベントは実際には国際的なイベントです
Invited Nam Kwong laser inventor Zhong Chunxiuer to give a speech in Taiwan
Nam Kwong レーザー発明者の Zhong Chunxiuer 氏を台湾での講演に招待
We also organize activities for the International Year of Wisdom in various universities
また、さまざまな大学で国際知恵年に向けた活動を企画しています。
Also includes photoelectric week at Nangang International Exhibition Center
南港国際展示センターでの光電ウィークも含まれます
There were about 50,000 to 60,000 people present
約5万人から6万人が参加した
So this event is actually a big event
ということで、このイベントは実はビッグイベントなんです
In fact, this activity is very
実はこの活動はとても
It also includes organizing some activities in middle schools and high schools
中学校や高校での実施も含まれます
this briefing and some presentations
このブリーフィングといくつかのプレゼンテーション
There are also workshops with popular science lectures
人気の科学講座を開催するワークショップもあり
from january to december
1月から12月まで
There are various activities every month
毎月様々な行事を行っております
A total of more than 50 presentations
合計50件以上のプレゼンテーション
In North, Central, South, and East
北、中、南、東で
For details, if you are interested, you can see
詳細は、興味のある方はご覧ください
The RYL2015 International Year of Light Part Review
RYL2015 国際光年パートレビュー
This page is actually
実はこのページは、
at the United Nations
国連で
Follow the website in Taiwan
台湾のウェブサイトをフォローしてください
can see the link
リンクを見ることができます
There are movies and photos
動画も写真もあるよ
I won't go into details
詳細には触れません
this is his link
これは彼のリンクです
It is our Taiwan International Year of Light
今年は台湾国際光年です
Website, Lantern Festival website
ウェブサイト、ランタンフェスティバルウェブサイト
There is also a link and address of the review video
レビュー動画のリンクとアドレスもあります
Designed by Sun Qingcheng and the director of the Key Institute of Sun Central University
孫清成氏と孫中央大学重点研究所所長によって設計されました。
It is this LOGO plus in Taiwan
台湾ではこのロゴプラスです
This is a mountain with three veins
これは三脈の山です
Well, that is to say, all the people in Taiwan who participated in this activity
さて、つまり、この活動に参加した台湾の皆さん
There are probably more than two thousand people
たぶん2000人以上いるだろう
2,000 person-times, because including production officers and trainees
生産担当者と研修生を含むため、2,000人時間
To sum it up, why do you want to do this?
要約すると、なぜこれをやりたいのですか？
because we think light is actually very important
私たちは光が実際に非常に重要だと考えているからです
It will have a major impact on Taiwan's future culture and people's livelihood technology
台湾の将来の文化と民生技術に大きな影響を与える
Those of us who may have bought stocks know that
株を買ったことがある人ならわかると思いますが、
At present, Largan is still the stock king or the stock queen.
現時点では、ラーガンはまだ株式王または株式女王です。
That is to say, mobile phones around the world
つまり、世界中の携帯電話
this lens
このショット
That's only us in Taiwan
台湾では私たちだけです
This compound lens can be done
この複合レンズができる
the size of a grain of rice
米粒ほどの大きさ
confidential optics
機密光学系
Then the lens module like this
するとレンズモジュールはこんな感じ
Can be marketed all over the world
世界中で販売可能
Then everyone depends on us
そうすれば、誰もが私たちを頼りにします
This confidential optical lens
この機密光学レンズ
do this
これを行う
camera lens
カメラのレンズ
So this is a very important development
これは非常に重要な開発です
In addition to that
それに加えて
the year of international
国際的な年
It's actually a rare opportunity
実は滅多にない機会です
Put us Taiwan on top of the international
私たち台湾を国際の頂点に立たせましょう
there is one
ここに一つ
a chance to show
見せるチャンス
A platform to communicate with everyone
みんなとコミュニケーションできるプラットフォーム
so
それで
We will work very hard to do this
私たちはそのために一生懸命努力します
Well, I spent about ten minutes telling this story.
さて、この話をするのに約 10 分を費やしました。
Then I will report to you next time.
それではまた次回ご報告させていただきます。
is the recent story of optics
最近の光学の話です
What happened to optics recently?
最近光学に何が起こったのでしょうか？
I'll probably tell you guys first
おそらく最初に皆さんにお伝えします
what is photonics
フォトニクスとは何ですか
that photonics
そのフォトニクス
You can imagine lasers, like this laser pointer
このレーザーポインターのようなレーザーを想像してみてください
Then CCD KEMENR, CCD KEMENR won the Nobel Prize
その後、CCD KEMENR、CCD KEMENRがノーベル賞を受賞
This Guangqian Gaokun also won the Nobel Prize for Guangqian Communication
この広前高君は広前コミュニケーションでノーベル賞も受賞した
Then the focusing of light, because of optical focusing, we have microscopes and astronomical telescopes for such things
それから光の集束、光学集束ですから、そういうもの用の顕微鏡や天体望遠鏡があります。
Then, solar cells, our southern campus is at Shalun Farm, which will become a demonstration base for green energy photoelectricity in the future
次に、太陽電池、私たちの南キャンパスは沙崙農場にあり、将来グリーンエネルギー光発電の実証基地になります
Then, there will be solar cells everywhere
そうすれば、どこにでも太陽電池が設置されるでしょう
As for BioSensor, BioSensor has gradually become more and more important in Taiwan, because I don’t have
バイオセンサーについては、台湾ではバイオセンサーの重要性が徐々に高まっています。
Showed a lot of other market development information, currently Taiwan's optoelectronics industry
現在の台湾のオプトエレクトロニクス産業に関する他の多くの市場開発情報を示しました。
In the past two years, this Bio Photonics has accounted for 8%
過去 2 年間で、このバイオフォトニクスが 8% を占めています
Is to grow gradually from scratch
ゼロから徐々に成長させていくこと
Slowly start growing over five years
5年かけてゆっくりと成長を始める
Many things are Bio Sensors
多くのものはバイオセンサーです
And there is Bio Image
そしてバイオイメージもあります
Bio Image actually spoke at Norbert Herschel in 2014
Bio Image は 2014 年に Norbert Herschel で実際に講演しました
Just for Bio Image
バイオイメージ専用
If I work on this aspect, I will try to find a way to report to you.
この点に取り組んだら、皆さんに報告できる方法を見つけようと思います。
So my next story will be divided into three parts
ということで、次回のお話は3部に分かれます
The first part is Green Life
最初の部分はグリーンライフです
The second one is Bin Light
2つ目はビンライトです
The third part is Future World
第三部はフューチャーワールド
What is Green Light What is Bin Light What is Future World
グリーンライトとは ビンライトとは フューチャーワールドとは
I will take three examples individually and report to you
3つの例を個別に取り上げてご報告します
那 Photonics for Green World
那 Photonics for Green World
That is to say now everyone knows this
つまり、今では誰もが知っていることです
Human civilization has developed to this day
人類の文明は今日まで発展してきました
What everyone wants is a very clean
誰もが望んでいるのはとてもきれいなことです
A very healthy and hygienic environment
非常に健康的で衛生的な環境
A very beautiful future world
とても美しい未来の世界
So we all say that we hope that we can not consume
だから私たちは皆、消費できないことを願っていると言います
No matter what is consumed, nothing is consumed
何を消費しても何も消費されない
no waste
無駄がない
And keep it very simple, very clean
そしてそれを非常にシンプルに、非常にクリーンにしてください
need to be able to do this
これができる必要がある
In fact science is a very important development
実際、科学は非常に重要な発展です
So how to do this
それで、これをどうやって行うか
The first point is to say
最初のポイントはこう言うことです
Many things in human civilization are being explored
人類文明の多くのことが探求されています
That is to say we used to do
つまり、私たちはかつてそうしていました
But can we do better now
しかし、今より良くできるだろうか
One of the most typical is this solar auxiliary device
最も代表的なのがこのソーラー補助装置です。
What is a tutoring device basically?
そもそも個別指導デバイスとは何ですか?
basically it says
基本的にそれは言う
The sun's light travels 8 minutes to the earth
太陽の光は地球まで8分で届きます
Then humans on the earth develop some devices
その後、地球上の人類はいくつかの装置を開発しました
These devices convert the energy of this light into electrons
これらのデバイスは、この光のエネルギーを電子に変換します。
convert photons into electrons
光子を電子に変換する
This electron can then be used to light a light bulb
この電子は電球を点灯するために使用できます
or cooking
または料理
Or do other uses of electric vehicles
あるいは電気自動車の他の用途を行う
Harrie Walter of Caltech
加州理工的Harrie Walter
One of the world's leading teams in their lab
研究室の世界有数のチームの 1 つ
Caltech also has one of the world's leading green energy centers
カリフォルニア工科大学には世界有数のグリーン エネルギー センターもあります
he is the director of the center
彼はセンターの所長です
He proposed that on the solar cell
彼は太陽電池について次のように提案した
put these very tiny nanoparticles
これらの非常に小さなナノ粒子を入れます
These nanoparticles allow these light
これらのナノ粒子はこれらの光を可能にします
During this process
このプロセス中に
Generate more electrons during the action
動作中により多くの電子を生成します
can be more efficient
より効率的になる可能性があります
How to put these nanometer metal particles
このナノメートルの金属粒子をどのように配置するか
can be placed on the most surface
ほとんどの表面に設置可能
It can be placed at the interface of this semiconductor
この半導体の界面に配置することができます
That can also be placed behind this
この後ろに置くこともできます
Do some unavoidable structure behind
背後に避けられない構造を作る
So they did a lot of experiments like this
そこで彼らはこのような実験をたくさん行いました
to study
勉強する
It was found that the efficiency can be improved
効率を改善できることが分かりました
Then how much would you say the efficiency has improved?
では、どれくらい効率が上がったと思いますか？
The highest and ultimate efficiency of human civilization
人類文明の最高かつ究極の効率
That is, 100 photons
つまり、100個のフォトン
How many can be converted into electrons
電子に変換できるのは何個ですか
about 20 or so
20人くらい
What about the 20?
20はどうですか？
if it can improve
改善できれば
Assume 10%
10% と仮定します
That means
つまり、
That's 20, that's two more
それは 20、それはあと 2
You may not mind
気にしないかもしれません
But what?
でも何？
The photon is actually very, very large
光子は実際には非常に大きいです
energy from the sun to the earth
太陽から地球へのエネルギー
It's actually very, very strong
実はとてもとても強いんです
very rich
とても裕福な
a lot of
非常多的
So a very small increase in efficiency
したがって、効率の向上はごくわずかです
In fact, it is a very big step in human civilization.
実際、これは人類の文明における非常に大きな一歩です。
so this is a very important thing
これはとても重要なことです
Therefore, all countries in the world, especially advanced countries, attach great importance to this point.
したがって、世界各国、特に先進国はこの点を非常に重視しています。
We are short of a round of professors at Tsinghua University in Taiwan
台湾の清華大学には教授が不足しています
His Tianan battery like this in CIGS
CIGSでの彼の天安バッテリーはこんな感じ
There are many kinds of Tianan batteries
天安バッテリーにはたくさんの種類があります
Some are using Silicon with fine
細かいシリコンを使用しているものもあります
Some are made of diversified metals
さまざまな金属で作られたものもあります
Tianan battery made of multiple compound semiconductor materials
複数の化合物半導体材料で作られた天安電池
it incorporates particles of gold
金の粒子が組み込まれています
There is also an east-west interlayer of the fluidized compartment.
流動化区画の東西中間層もあります。
He found that he could actually improve this efficiency
彼はこの効率を実際に改善できることを発見しました
Can be increased from 8.3% to 10.3%
8.3%から10.3%まで増加可能
increased by 2%
2%増加
You'd say 2% is no big deal
2%なんて大したことないと言うだろう
Actually 2% is pretty big
実際2%ってかなり大きいよな
Because 0.5% is a big deal
0.5%って大きいから
Don't talk about 2%
2%については話さないでください
So his job is a very important job
だから彼の仕事はとても重要な仕事だ
And he illuminates from different angles
そして彼はさまざまな角度から光を当てます
no mezzanine like this
こんな中二階はないよ
with such a mezzanine
こんな中二階で
His performance can be from 350 nm wavelength to
彼のパフォーマンスは 350 nm の波長から
This wavelength of nearly 1000 nanometers
この1000ナノメートル近い波長
have a very good performance
とても良いパフォーマンスをする
very balanced performance
非常にバランスの取れたパフォーマンス
for different angles of incidence
さまざまな入射角に対応
He can have a very high absorption
彼は非常に高い吸収力を持っています
it's not easy
簡単ではない
What about Professor Chen Wenwen from National Taiwan University?
国立台湾大学の陳文文教授はどうでしょうか？
he is also very clever
彼はまたとても賢いです
He made one like this
彼はこんなものを作りました
This is a PVP plain glue
これはPVPプレーン接着剤です
then snag
それから引っかかる
in the process of spinning
紡いでいる途中
It puts silver grains inside this easy
この中に銀粒を入れて簡単に
then snag
それから引っかかる
Then when spinning
それから回転するときに
It first puts a small metal carrier
まず小さな金属キャリアを置きます
and turn like this
そしてこのように向きを変える
like faux sand
人工砂のような
when it was like sand
砂のようだったとき
you will find
見つけるだろう
It can imitate sand like this first
まずはこんな感じで砂を模倣できます
Then it can turn the artificial sand 90 degrees again
その後、人工砂を再び90度回転させることができます
Then imitate sand like this
じゃあ砂をこんな風に真似してみよう
After imitation sand
模造砂の後
Inside the plastic PVP inside
内部にはプラスチックPVPが入っています
Contains some gold particles
若干の金粒子が含まれています
Containing percentages from 1.39 to 0.36 to 0.07
1.39 ～ 0.36 ～ 0.07 のパーセンテージを含む
The less it contains, of course the finer the silk can be drawn
もちろん、含有量が少ないほど、より細いシルクを描くことができます。
kinda like silk
シルクみたいな
Then it does this thing
それからこのことをします
It then puts this thing inside the solar cell
それからこれを太陽電池の中に入れます
This organic semiconductor solar cell
この有機半導体太陽電池は
at this
この時点で
top of electrode
電極上部
then he found
それから彼は見つけた
It's in the spectrum of visible light
それは可視光のスペクトル内にあります
his external quantum efficiency
彼の外部量子効率
Can be increased from 40% 50% to 60%
40% 50% から 60% まで増加可能
So this is also a very important development.
したがって、これも非常に重要な進展です。
So our scientist in Taiwan
それで、台湾の科学者は
Work very hard to do these state-of-the-art work
これらの最先端の仕事に一生懸命取り組む
Also at the same time in this
こちらも同時に
Rice University
ライス大学
Rice University in America
アメリカのライス大学
they have a very amazing one
彼らはとても素晴らしいものを持っています
American Academy of Sciences
アメリカ科学アカデミー
He heard that he is now an academician of four academies
彼は現在4つのアカデミーの学者であると聞いた
called Niamihara's
ナイアミハラと呼ばれる
He was the first in the world to propose
彼は世界で最初にプロポーズした
Put this Daimi's metal pellets
これにダイミの金属ペレットを入れます
This kind of photothermal therapy for cancer
この種のがん光熱療法
Just let the metal particles like this absorb
このような金属粒子を吸収させてください
Then heat the cancer cells to death
次にガン細胞を加熱して死滅させます
This is their animal experiment
これは彼らの動物実験です
And they've been approved by the FDA
そしてFDAの承認を受けています
to do some human experiments
人体実験をするために
12 days after the tumor
腫瘍発生から12日後
just end up scum
結局クズになるだけ
becomes very very small
とてもとても小さくなる
That is to say, it is very effective to do such a thing
つまり、このようなことを行うと非常に効果的です
Those are the things that make human life
それらは人間の命を作るものです
some things that could be better
もっと良くなるかもしれないいくつかのこと
Professor Huang Guozhu at Tsinghua University in Taiwan
台湾・清華大学の黄国珠教授
too done such a thing
君もそんなことをする
but he is smarter
しかし彼は賢いです
He took the nanoparticle
彼はナノ粒子を入れた
made like a sea urchin
ウニのように作られた
one by one thorn
一つ一つの棘
then you can see this sea urchin
そうするとこのウニが見えます
This is the magnetic marker at 100 nanometers
これは100ナノメートルの磁気マーカーです
Then this is about a few hundred nanometers
これは約数百ナノメートルです
Five or six hundred nanometers
500ナノメートルか600ナノメートル
such sea urchin
そんなウニ
then a lot of thorny words
それからたくさんの棘のある言葉
he made the mouse
彼はネズミを作りました
to deduce
推測する
After having an Essie bag culture
エッシーバッグ文化を経て
Let particles like this adsorb on the Essie bag
このような粒子をエッシーバッグに吸着させます
Then it shines infrared light in
次に赤外線を照射します
It can generate more of these free machines
これらの無料マシンをさらに生成できます
Then heat the root and kill the Essie bag
次に根を加熱してエッシーバッグを殺します
Then the Essie bag will shrink
そしたらエッシーバッグは縮むよ
this was very very successful
これはとてもとても成功しました
You may ask, what is the relationship between the thorn and the particle?
とげと粒子の間にはどのような関係があるのか​​と疑問に思うかもしれません。
Because they make glutinous rice balls, why do you make sea urchins?
もちむすびを作るのに、なぜウニを作るのか？
It's simple, stab a lot of words
シンプルに言葉をたくさん刺して
It is easier to receive these light and generate heat
この光を受けやすくなり、熱が発生しやすくなります。
So this is easy to do
だからこれは簡単にできるんです
Ms. Liu Ruxi from the Department of Chemistry, National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学化学科のLiu Ruxiさん
he is better
彼の方が良い
He should do the thorn, it's not easy to do it small
彼は難しいことをやるべきだ、小さなことをやるのは簡単ではない
so he made it small
それで彼はそれを小さくしました
You see this is a 20 nanometer scale
これは 20 ナノメートルのスケールであることがわかります
The one just now was a 100-nanometer scale
さっきのは100ナノメートルスケールだった
5. As big as 600 nanometers
5. 600ナノメートルもの大きさ
There is a limit to how many pills you can swallow
飲み込める錠剤の数には制限がある
If it is very small, it can swallow a lot
非常に小さい場合は、たくさん飲み込むことができます
swallow a lot of words
たくさんの言葉を飲み込む
Ant Xiong Bin
アント・シオン・ビン
it's powerful
それは強力です
so you can
だからあなたはできる
It is easy to enter directly from the cell membrane
細胞膜から直接侵入しやすい
because it's too small
小さすぎるから
After cell membrane invasion
細胞膜侵入後
Demonstrate like this
このようにデモンストレーションします
You cover this one up
あなたはこれを隠蔽します
that cancer cell died
そのガン細胞は死んだ
these are cancer cells
これらは癌細胞です
are cancer cells
がん細胞です
Cancer cells cultured on glass
ガラス上で培養したがん細胞
Then you light mask
それからあなたはマスクをライトします
because these cancer cells
なぜなら、これらのがん細胞は
After swallowing such small particles
このような小さな粒子を飲み込んだ後
easy to kill
簡単に殺せる
So this is a very interesting development
これは非常に興味深い展開です
Then Li Xianming from the Institute of Chemistry, Academia Sinica
次に、中央研究院化学研究所のLi Xianming氏です。
researcher
研究員
he is better
彼の方が良い
Because just after the light went down
ちょうど照明が落ちた直後だったので、
Your skin and flesh will block some of the light
あなたの皮膚と肉は光の一部を遮断します
Can't get in
入れません
So he wanted a hood
それで彼はフードが欲しかったのです
He said he could get in
彼は入ることができると言った
It must be infrared light with a relatively long wavelength
比較的波長の長い赤外線である必要があります
So he put these things just now
それで彼は今これらのものを置きました
put on a so-called up-conversion material
いわゆるアップコンバート素材を装着する
Up-conversion means that I use a long wavelength to enter
アップコンバートとは、長い波長を使用して入力することを意味します
it converts it to a shorter wavelength
より短い波長に変換します
But you clean the skin and these tissues of these animals
でもあなたはこれらの動物の皮膚や組織をきれいにします
When hitting these refugee particles that can kill cancer cells
がん細胞を殺す可能性のあるこれらの難民粒子に当たると
it converts
それは変換します
so it doesn't waste the light
光を無駄にしないように
and it can go deep into the organization
そしてそれは組織の奥深くまで浸透する可能性があります
Therefore, Professor Li Xianming and Researcher Li Xianming's
したがって、Li Xianming 教授と Li Xianming 研究者の
This so-called up-conversion
いわゆるアップコンバートです
It's easy for you to see
見るのは簡単です
it uses something like this upconversion
このアップコンバートのようなものを使用します
allows you to see these cells very clearly
これらの細胞を非常にはっきりと見ることができます
this is a very important development
これは非常に重要な進展です
just talked about green
緑の話をしたばかりです
Green must be related to the environment
緑は環境に関連している必要があります
So this is British
だからこれはイギリス人だよ
Professor Durant of Inpirit College
Inpirit College的Durant教授
He has one idea
彼には一つの考えがある
a future environment
未来の環境
Future environment sun shines down
太陽が降り注ぐ未来環境
and then in this various ways
そして、このようにさまざまな方法で
convert sunlight energy into chemical energy
太陽光エネルギーを化学エネルギーに変換する
or converted into this mechanical energy
またはこの機械エネルギーに変換される
or converted into electrical energy
または電気エネルギーに変換される
Then store energy in this way
そして、このようにしてエネルギーを蓄えます
use as a human
人間として使う
Then don't develop something like nuclear energy, which is very dangerous
それなら原子力のようなものは開発しないでください、それは非常に危険です
Or not to develop the highly dangerous thermal power generation
危険性の高い火力発電を開発しないのか
things like burning coal
石炭を燃やすようなもの
Because in fact, the PN2.5 produced by burning coal
なぜなら、実際には石炭を燃やすことによってPN2.5が生成されるからです。
Worse than a nuclear power plant
原子力発電所よりも悪い
So here are some of his wonderful thoughts
ここで彼の素晴らしい考えをいくつか紹介します
but all these beautiful thoughts
でもこれらすべての美しい考えは
It involves the efficiency of converting photons into electrons
光子を電子に変換する効率が関係します
The problem of the efficiency of converting photons into electrons
光子を電子に変換する効率の問題
In 1972, the Japanese discovered a very important thing, which is the effect of beauty in light.
1972 年に日本人は、光の美しさの効果という非常に重要なことを発見しました。
There is a semiconductor carbon dioxide, which can effectively convert photons into electrons
光子を電子に効果的に変換できる半導体二酸化炭素があります
Happens when it's unlikely, becomes a lot when it's rare
起こりそうにないときは起こり、まれなときは多くなる
So a very important milestone is the hydrolysis experiment called Guangximei
したがって、非常に重要なマイルストーンは、Guangximei と呼ばれる加水分解実験です
Such a substance of carbon dioxide is called Guangchumei substance
このような二酸化炭素の物質を光中美物質といいます。
You may have seen that there are many toilets in Taiwan that are written by Guang Chumei.
台湾には、広初梅が書いたトイレがたくさんあるのを見たことがあるかもしれません。
Then many supplies write about what are the cosmetic products used for light treatment? They are used for antibacterial
では、光線治療に使用される化粧品は何ですか? 抗菌に使用されるかについて、多くの製品が書いています。
Deodorizing and antibacterial, because it will produce some
消臭・抗菌作用があるので、
These electrons make bacteria uncomfortable
これらの電子は細菌に不快感を与えます
prevent bacteria from growing
細菌の増殖を防ぐ
It can also be used for water treatment
水処理にも使えます
And do water decomposition
そして水を分解します
There are many other good uses
他にも良い使い方がたくさんあります
That Century Han did the best
センチュリーハンは頑張った
Professor Yang Peidong from Berkeley
バークレーのヤン・ペイドン教授
He developed something like this
彼はこのようなものを開発しました
Some very special electrodes for hydrolysis
加水分解用の非常に特殊な電極
This electrode has these photocatalyst nanoparticles
この電極にはこの光触媒ナノ粒子が含まれています
Then he can effectively
そうすれば彼は効果的に
Speed ​​up the hydrolysis rate of such a
このような加水分解速度を加速します。
efficiency improvement
効率向上
Professor Liu Ruxi, Department of Chemistry, National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学化学科 Liu Ruxi 教授
He is also working very hard on this aspect.
彼はこの面でも非常に熱心に取り組んでいます。
That is not lost to Professor Yang Peidong of Berkeley University
それはバークレー大学のヤン・ペイドン教授にも負けていない
They use this special effect of surface electric resonance
彼らはこの表面電気共鳴の特殊効果を利用しています。
On such a photocatalyst, some small nanoparticles are adsorbed
このような光触媒には、いくつかの小さなナノ粒子が吸着されています
These are tiny nanoparticles that allow incoming light to generate photoelectrons
これらは、入射光によって光電子を生成できる小さなナノ粒子です。
Then let these photoelectrons oscillate inside
次に、これらの光電子を内部で振動させます
It's just the cloud wrapping around and never going away
それはただ雲が包み込んで決して離れることはない
It's not like you come in and have a talk and then leave to play a safe ball.
入ってきて話をして、安全なプレーをするために去っていくようなものではありません。
it doesn't come in, it stays in
それは入ってこない、残っている
So it can effectively localize photons in a small range
そのため、狭い範囲で効果的に光子の位置を特定できます
and then to produce a strong effect
そして強い効果を生み出すために
This effect allows the photochemical reaction to produce hydrolysis
この効果により、光化学反応による加水分解が可能になります。
So some experiments like this are conducted by Chen Yulin, Department of Physics, National Taiwan University.
このような実験は、国立台湾大学物理学科のChen Yulin氏によって行われています。
This Mr. Chen is doing some interesting things in my laboratory
この陳さんは私の研究室で面白いことをやっています
He just took the discarded CD and took it
彼は捨てられたCDをそのまま手に取った
do an interesting experiment
面白い実験をしてください
That is to say, on the CD for flight
つまり、フライト用のCDでは
It is very simple to let it grow some small light and beautiful materials
とても小さくて軽くて美しい素材を成長させるのはとても簡単です
Then put this flying CD drive
次に、この空飛ぶ CD ドライブを置きます
just hug me
ただ私を抱きしめてください
and put it in here
そしてここに入れてください
Then it can put this dye
それからこの染料を入れることができます
some dyes just do the processing
一部の染料は処理を行うだけです
After processing these chemical dyes
これらの化学染料を加工した後、
will become
となります
At first a colored false base
まずは着色した疑似ベース
it is a standard dye
それは標準的な染料です
Then do it and suck it up from above
じゃあやって、上から吸い上げて
dripping down on this flying disc
この空飛ぶ円盤に滴り落ちる
The chicken soup underneath will turn into clear water
下の鶏スープが透明な水に変わります
Just ask me where those dye molecules go
染料分子がどこへ行くのか聞いてください
Then CO2 turns into H2O and runs away
そしてCO2はH2Oになって逃げていきます。
Just dispersed in the air and went away
ただ空中に散らばって去って行った
so what can he do with it
それで彼はそれで何ができるでしょうか
It can be used for waste water treatment
排水処理にも使用できます
Wastewater Treatment Jobs
廃水処理の仕事
because he can decompose some
彼は一部を分解できるので、
decompose
分解する
It is to give some harmful chemical substances to
有害な化学物質を与えることです
spies interrupted
スパイが中断した
Then what
じゃあ何
what about this matter
この件についてはどうですか
It's actually just a small project
それは実際には小さなプロジェクトにすぎません
Projects taught to students
学生に教えたプロジェクト
AAS
AAS
Also by BBC News in London, UK
英国ロンドンのBBCニュースからも
evening News
夕方のニュース
just say you know
知っていると言ってください
The Taiwanese took the CD for the plane
台湾人はCDを飛行機に持ち込む
to treat sewer water
下水道水を処理するために
that water is still drinkable
その水はまだ飲めます
You know when word gets around
いつその言葉が広まるか知っていますか
global report
グローバルレポート
And then we got close to this one or two hundred letters
そして、この 100 文字か 200 文字に近づいた
asked us to give them that movie
その映画を見せてほしいと私たちに頼んだ
they are going to do
彼らはするつもりです
Then there are many high school students in the United States
それからアメリカには高校生がたくさんいます
Said they were going to bake
彼らは焼くつもりだと言いました
do this
これを行う
good
良い
Then our hard science center
それから私たちのハードサイエンスセンター
He's in the researcher, he's actually just been in water treatment
彼は研究者ですが、実際には水処理に携わったばかりです
In fact, he told me that a while ago, everyone was very careful with food
実際、少し前まではみんな食べ物にとても気をつけていたと彼は私に言いました。
Especially pesticides, and some toxic chemicals
特に農薬や一部の有毒化学物質
Affects food, he does one thing in particular
食べ物に影響を与える、彼は特別なことをします
He asked if there was any way to quickly test the residual pesticides
彼は、残留農薬を迅速に検査する方法はないか尋ねました。
So he just made normal slides like this
それで彼はこのような普通のスライドを作っただけです
It's an A4-sized slide, and he used it to make some Naimi structures on it
それは A4 サイズのスライドで、彼はそれを使ってナイミのいくつかの構造を作成しました。
Then, in these Nami structures, he can build them piece by piece
そして、これらのナミの構造物を少しずつ組み立てることができます。
He can lower the things you want to test on top
彼はあなたがテストしたいものを一番上に下げることができます
For example, tearing down the leaves and smashing them into pieces, lowering them to the top
たとえば、葉を引き裂いて粉々にし、上まで降ろします。
Then you can see the real-time test from the above performance
上記のパフォーマンスからリアルタイム テストを確認できます。
This one doesn't seem to work
これは機能しないようです
Let me tell you that this is its Akuan No. 1
言わせてください、これがその悪庵No.1です
This is a plastic sheet in A4 size
A4サイズのビニールシートです
it just has a thing
それはただ物を持っているだけです
just put it in
ただ入れてください
Stamped stamped stamped
スタンプされたスタンプされた
covered many, many nanostructures
非常に多くのナノ構造をカバー
These nanostructures are stamped one by one like this
このようにナノ構造を一つ一つスタンプしていきます
These seals are sensors
このシールはセンサーです
This sensor sees with the naked eye
このセンサーは肉眼で見ることができます
very clever
非常に賢い
Its sensitivity is a world record
その感度は世界記録です
broken world record
破られた世界記録
very high sensitivity
非常に高い感度
You can see the color directly with the naked eye
肉眼で直接色が確認できる
So it recently did an interesting technology transfer
そこで最近、興味深い技術移転を行いました
Just put your phone directly on its sensor
携帯電話をセンサーの上に直接置くだけです
You can see it just inside this
この中にすぐ見えます
The concentration of that glory is from the right
その栄光の結集は右から
glory few to left glory many
少数の栄光を残して多くの栄光を残す
You can see how much glory you have when you drop it
落としてみるとどれだけの栄光があるかわかるよ
You can know in which grid
どのグリッドにあるかを知ることができます
So the phone can take a picture
携帯電話で写真が撮れるので、
After taking a picture with the phone
スマホで写真を撮った後
The mobile phone has an APP
携帯電話にはAPPがあります
I can tell you
教えられます
You are now honored, what is the glory in Zen language?
今は光栄ですが、禅語で栄光とは何でしょうか？
he told me yesterday
彼は昨日私に言った
Now the most commonly tested is edamide
現在最も一般的に検査されているのはエダミドです
The limit of Yidaan residue is 0.5ppm
Yidaan残留物の制限は0.5ppmです
to 3 ppm
3ppmまで
Usually more than 3 ppm
通常3ppm以上
The limit of how deep they can be measured is 0.01
深さを測定できる限界は 0.01 です
That is to say, they have high seniority
つまり、年功序列が高いのです
This is what they actually measured
これが実際に計測したものです
They will cooperate with Glory
彼らはグローリーに協力するだろう
at the end of last year
昨年末に
This job also held a press conference
この仕事も記者会見を行いました
It's the honor meeting they opened
それは彼らが開いた栄光の集会だ
So some work on this
それで、これに少し取り組んでください
In fact, Taiwan does not
実際、台湾はそうではない
I have also done a lot, and it is very advanced
私もたくさんのことをやりましたが、それは非常に高度です
It's just that many people are very busy with certain things
ただ、多くの人が特定のことにとても忙しいだけです
don't know its development
その発展を知りません
So today I hope to have the opportunity to report to you
そこで今日は皆様にご報告させていただく機会があればと思います
The second part is about this
第二部はこれについてです
Part of BinLine
BinLine の一部
The part of the BinLine that says
BinLine の部分
production of light, use of light
光の生成、光の利用
And what about these things?
そして、これらのことについてはどうですか？
some of the latest developments
最新の開発の一部
Professor Xiang Zhang at Berkeley University
バークレー大学のシャン・ジャン教授
He is also an academician of our Academia Sinica
彼は中央研究院の学者でもあります。
and Terry Olden from Northwestern
そしてノースウェスタン出身のテリー・オルデン
The two of them are in this
二人はこの中にいます
The smallest light source in the world
世界最小の光源
well done lab
よくやった研究室
One is nanorods with so-called fluidized spacers
1つは、いわゆる流動スペーサーを備えたナノロッドです。
on a silver surface
銀色の表面に
Then the world's smallest
それから世界最小
Laser, then this is the spectrum of the light emitted by the laser
レーザーの場合、これはレーザーから発せられる光のスペクトルです。
Very uniform, very good
非常に均一で、非常に良い
Then the other Terry Ogden they use a different fluid to flow through
そしてもう一人のテリー・オグデンは、別の液体を使って流れています。
A metal particle like this will be found to say
このような金属粒子が見つかると、次のようになります。
They can produce different liquids when flowing through such particles
このような粒子の中を流れるときに、さまざまな液体を生成する可能性があります。
If the refractive index is different, the wavelength of the laser light it produces is not the same
屈折率が異なると、生成されるレーザー光の波長は異なります。
Then the two of them are currently known to be the best in the world.
そして、彼ら2人は現在世界最高であることが知られています。
Then we in Taiwan might as well let Professor Guo Shangzhi of Tsinghua University
それなら、台湾の私たちも清華大学の郭尚志教授に任せたほうがいいかもしれません。
After the two of them, he also published the so-called
二人の後に、彼はまた、いわゆる
Nano Isshiki made of a column made of nitrided nano
窒化ナノ柱状ナノ一色
The nano particles
ナノ粒子
What is the difference between Nanolaser and Nanolaser just now?
先ほどのナノレーザーとナノレーザーの違いは何ですか？
The nano-laser just now is not a semiconductor laser
先ほどのナノレーザーは半導体レーザーではありません
That's a semiconductor laser
それが半導体レーザーです
And it is at long temperature
しかも高温なので
Yishi that can be produced at a long temperature
高温で製造できるイシ
And its efficiency and the light produced by its power
その効率とその力によって生み出される光
are very very strong
都非常非常的強
And the quality of light is much better than before
そして光の質は以前よりもはるかに優れています
Much better quality published by any other lab
他のラボが発行したものよりもはるかに優れた品質
So teacher Guo's nano laser
それで郭先生のナノレーザー
In fact its directionality
実はその方向性は
And its temperature control is very, very good
そしてその温度管理は非常に優れています
I won't go into details
詳細には触れません
In addition, Mr. Guo recently developed a variety of different wavelengths
さらに、郭氏は最近、さまざまな波長を開発しました。
that is, different colors
つまり色が違う
various nanolasers
さまざまなナノレーザー
And they're doing really well
そして彼らは本当にうまくやっている
This is the smallest semiconductor laser in the world
これは世界最小の半導体レーザーです
It's only 50 nanometers wide and 200 nanometers long
幅はわずか 50 ナノメートル、長さは 200 ナノメートルです
This record has not been broken so far
この記録は今のところ破られていない
So it is the light of our Taiwan
それは私たちの台湾の光です
Well, he's also the director of our Synchrotron Radiation Center.
そうですね、彼は私たちの放射光センターの所長でもあります。
Professor of Department of Physics, Tsinghua University
清華大学物理学科教授
In addition, this Professor Zhang Xiangzhang
さらに、この張祥章教授は、
He also developed a type that is like a disc
円盤のようなタイプも開発した
But this disk is very small
しかし、このディスクは非常に小さいです
Everyone, take a look, this is 1micron
皆さん見てください、これが1ミクロンです
If it is 1micron, everyone knows that your hair is about 500micron
1ミクロンなら、髪の毛が500ミクロン程度であることは誰もが知っています。
5 percent of your hair
髪の毛の5パーセント
so small a small ring
とても小さい、小さな指輪
plate, this plate will produce this circular circular resonant gun laser
プレート、このプレートはこの円形の共鳴銃レーザーを生成します
His advantage is that he is very
彼の利点は、彼が非常に優れていることです
very very narrow wavelength
波長はとてもとても狭いです
very very thin
とてもとても良い
Such research is rare
このような研究は珍しい
Professor No. 4 of the Department of Electrical Engineering, National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学電気工学部第4教授
He also used similar techniques in two-dimensional materials
彼は二次元マテリアルでも同様のテクニックを使用しました。
Molidae
モリダ科
It's on the sample of second fluidized wood
2回目の流動木材のサンプルにあります
found that if you put a sample like this
このようなサンプルを置くと、
The resulting quantum efficiency
結果として得られる量子効率
is the efficiency with which photons generate electrons
光子が電子を生成する効率です
Can be improved from 0.9% to 99%
0.9%から99%まで改善可能
look this is very very bright
見てください、これはとてもとても明るいです
emit a lot of light
たくさんの光を発する
It's unfortunate that he was caught by this Arab
彼がこのアラブ人に捕まったのは残念だ
this
これ
Saudi Abo
サウジアラビアのアボ
dig this corner
この隅を掘ってください
University Awareness in Saudi Abo
サウジアラビアのアボにおける大学の啓発
He is no longer in National Taiwan University
彼はもう国立台湾大学に在籍していません
he did very very well
彼はとてもとてもよくやった
Of course, Professor Lu Luxi Liu of National Taiwan University
もちろん、国立台湾大学の劉魯希教授
he in the past few years
彼はここ数年で
He also did a very, very good job
彼もとてもとても良い仕事をしてくれました
I just mentioned that he made all kinds of
彼があらゆる種類のものを作ったと言いましたが、
Materials for nano optoelectronics
ナノオプトエレクトロニクス用材料
In fact his most famous
実際、彼の最も有名な
All LED companies in Taiwan
台湾のすべての LED 企業
hire him as a consultant
彼をコンサルタントとして雇う
It's his fluorescent powder
それは彼の蛍光パウダーです
he put this
彼はこれを置きました
Magnolite with four positive ions
4つのプラスイオンを持つマグノライト
of this float
このフロートの
He tried to get him some grooming
彼は身だしなみを整えてもらおうとした
then produce fluorescence
その後蛍光を発します
Then the color temperature of the fluorescent light it produces
次に、それが生成する蛍光の色温度
very very very human
とてもとてもとても人間らしい
that is
あれは
The previous color temperature was too high
以前の色温度は高すぎました
after too high
高すぎた後
Your eyes get dizzy after looking at it for a long time
長時間見ていると目がくらむ
Then the color temperature it produces is very mild
生成される色温度は非常に穏やかです
relatively low temperature
比較的低い温度
that won't hurt you
それはあなたを傷つけません
It is a nerve, and it will not produce some sequelae such as white viscera
神経なので内臓が白くなるなどの後遺症は出ません。
Speaking of this, in fact there is a Chen Yuren in our center, Professor Chen
そういえば、実は当センターには陳玉仁先生がいらっしゃいます、陳教授
He is very interested in this, he told me since I knew him
彼はこれに非常に興味がある、私が彼を知っていたときから彼は私に言った
He specializes in semiconductor optoelectronics, that is, someone who makes things like Guo Shangzhi and Guo Teacher
彼は半導体オプトエレクトロニクスを専門としており、つまり、Guo Shanzhi や Guo Teacher のようなものを作る人です。
He said that they found that they grow vegetables when they are very popular in Taiwan recently
最近台湾で野菜が人気なので栽培していることがわかったそうです。
Use this semiconductor light source to grow vegetables
この半導体光源を使って野菜を育てます
You say crazy, why don't you grow vegetables outside
君はクレイジーだと言う、なぜ外で野菜を育てたらいいの？
Planting vegetables outside, there will be insects after the light is on, and there is no way to control the environment
屋外に野菜を植えると、照明が点灯すると虫が発生し、環境を制御する方法がありません
Then when the typhoon comes, the vegetables will not grow
そうすると台風が来ると野菜が育たなくなる
So one dish costs hundreds of dollars, very expensive
つまり、一皿何百ドルもする、非常に高価です
So they say I grow vegetables by hand
だから私は手で野菜を育てていると言われています
the idea is very nice
アイデアはとてもいいです
Because our semiconductor industry in Taiwan is very good
台湾の半導体産業は非常に優れているため、
So LED made the world's number one
LEDが世界一になった
Use LED as light source to grow vegetables
LEDを光源として野菜を育てる
sell it to those deserts
それを砂漠に売ってください
Or sell to those Arab countries
あるいはアラブ諸国に売るか
it or those with bad environment
それや環境が悪い人
Very harsh places like the North Pole and the South Pole
北極や南極のような過酷な場所
The kind of area where it is dark for half a year
半年も暗い地域みたいな
isn't it good
いいじゃないですか
but he said he told me
でも彼は私に言ったと言いました
This vegetable has just been planted with a lot of technology and new regulations to grow vegetables
この野菜は、野菜を栽培するための多くの新しい技術規制を導入したばかりです
and after planting
そして植えた後は
Wow, the vegetables are growing so fast, so beautiful, so happy
わぁ、野菜の成長がとても早くて、とても美しくて、とても幸せです
And it is a water root plant, absolutely no pesticides
水根植物なので農薬は一切使用しておりません
Take it up and eat it, it makes a crackling sound
手に取って食べるとパチパチ音が鳴る
But that dish is neither sweet nor fragrant nor tasty
でもその料理は甘くも香りも美味しくもない
It is different from the natural vegetables outside
外の自然野菜とは違います
Then after many people give up
そして、多くの人が諦めた後、
after that segregation testimony
隔離証言の後
Some people slowly get the hang of it, he said it's not right
ゆっくりとコツを掴む人もいるが、彼はそれは正しくないと言う
He said what kind of light the vegetables should be exposed to when they were young
野菜が若いうちにどのような光を当てるべきかについて彼は言った
When will it grow and when will it shine?
いつ成長し、いつ輝きますか？
When it grows up to this time, it needs to be illuminated by this light, and when it is grown up, it must be illuminated by that light
ここまで成長したらこの光に照らされて、大きくなったらあの光に照らされて
Then what kind of light should I shine on the next few days?
では、これから数日間はどんな光を当てればいいのでしょうか？
That vegetable tastes delicious, and it's even better than vegetables grown outside
そういう食べ物は美味しいし、外で作った野菜より美味しいですよ。
That becomes a very ceremonial thing
それはとても儀式的なことになる
And what's even more strange is that he said that the light is terrible
そしてさらに奇妙なのは、光がひどいと彼が言ったことです
That is to say, after the people who make LEDs use a lot of light
つまり、LED を製造する人々が大量の光を使用した後、
Discover the light that your human eyes see
人間の目に見える光を発見してください
Thought it was all the same, it's not
どれも同じだと思っていたらそうではなかった
It's not just you that affects your sleep
睡眠に影響を与えるのはあなただけではありません
and with your nervous system
そして神経系に関しても
and your behavior
そしてあなたの行動
and your mood
そしてあなたの気分
And you are sports
そしてあなたはスポーツです
and your ability, and your memory
あなたの能力と記憶力
Also, your hormones
また、ホルモン
and yours
とあなたの
This cycle of physiological cellular responses
この生理学的細胞反応のサイクル
It also has something to do with your biological clock.
それは体内時計とも関係があります。
So it's the same with people
それは人も同じです
The same goes for dishes
食器も同様です
that dish at different times
その料理はさまざまな時に
In fact, the light he wants to be thin is different.
実は、痩せたい光は違うんです。
so this is amazing
だからこれはすごいです
So they started playing with the light
それで彼らは光で遊び始めました
Especially playing around with this different wavelength
特にこの異なる波長をいじってみよう
light sources of different colors
さまざまな色の光源
Then find a dense like this
次に、このような密集を見つけます
recipe to do what they want to do
やりたいことを実現するレシピ
Then this involves some photochemical reactions
これにはいくつかの光化学反応が含まれます
I won't go into details about that
それについては詳しくは説明しません
Well, this Chenye man, Professor Chen, is very powerful
さて、このチェンエという男、チェン教授は非常に強力です
So this design varies
なのでこのデザインは変わります
Refugee structure produces light of different wavelengths
難民構造は異なる波長の光を生成します
some like this, some with their heads off
このような人もいれば、頭を下げている人もいます
Some are pointy, some have broken heads
尖ったものもあれば、頭が折れているものもある
This kind of rice pillar
こんな稲柱も
then it produces different light
その後、異なる光が生成されます
Here you can see different colors of light
ここではさまざまな色の光を見ることができます
Red Dust Yellow Green Blue Electronics
レッドダストイエローグリーンブルーエレクトロニクス
Wavelength and its distribution
波長とその分布
all knowledge
すべての知識
these things are fun
これらのことは楽しいです
Another thing is
もう一つのことは、
Our Researcher Li Chaohuang
当社研究員 李朝黄
He likes to observe some behaviors of cells
彼は細胞の挙動を観察するのが好きです
he discovered that cells
彼はその細胞を発見した
see a cell, it's a dwarf cell
細胞を見てください、それは矮性細胞です
Here is red light, the wavelength is 1064
これは赤い光です、波長は1064です
Violet light here, the wavelength is 405
ここの紫色の光、波長は 405
As a result, the cell is very happy, and it continues to grow
その結果、細胞は非常に幸せになり、成長を続けます。
It's not happy here, it wants to retract its feet
ここでは満足できず、足を引っ込めたがる
After a period of time, the cells
一定の時間が経過すると、細胞は
So it means that even a single cell has a good understanding of light.
つまり、細胞一つでも光をよく理解しているということになります。
have likes and dislikes
好き嫌いがある
It comes from a study like this
このような研究から来ています
You can see that this is a culture of cancer cells
これはがん細胞の培養物であることがわかります
It hits a triangle with a light hitting this place
ここに光が当たると三角に当たる
Let's hit a square light here
ここに四角いライトを当ててみましょう
after a long time
長い時間が経ってから
Where the light is lit, the cells are scattered
光が当たるところには細胞が散らばる
where it doesn't like to be in this 473 nanometer light
この473ナノメートルの光の中にいることを好まない場所
That 473 is purple light
その473は紫色の光です
it doesn't like
それは好きではありません
so you see it spread out
それで、それが広がっているのがわかります
it's definitely no accident
それは間違いなく偶然ではありません
Then Mr. Li Changheng Li told me that
すると李長恒氏は私にこう言いました。
why ? because they are afraid of death
なぜ?彼らは死を恐れているからです。
He said after you look at the picture for a long time
あなたがその写真を長い間眺めていた後、彼はこう言いました。
the nuclei of these cells
これらの細胞の核
shrinking
萎縮的
will die
死んでしまいます
So it is afraid of death, so it spreads out
だから死が怖いから広がる
so this is very important
これはとても重要です
So this light actually, here is another movie
それで、この光は実際には、ここに別の映画があります
it puts the light outside on purpose
わざと外に光を当てます
Then slowly change this lit area
次に、この照らされた領域をゆっくりと変更します
Then the cell escapes
すると細胞が逃げ出す
just run away
ただ逃げるだけ
There is no light here, these are the areas of light
ここには光はありません、ここは光の領域です
You see the cells run away from here again
細胞たちがまたここから逃げ出すのがわかるだろう
That is to say, like Ganyang, you can design a trap
つまり、ガニャンのように罠を設計できるということだ。
Change it up so the cells are like your sheep
細胞を羊のように変えてみましょう
can do whatever you want
やりたいことは何でもできる
In addition, it also conducted an experiment
さらに、実験も行いました
But this doesn't seem to work, the movie won't move
しかし、これはうまくいかないようです、映画は動きません
That is to say, the light here will generate a
つまり、ここの光は
From light intensity to light weakness, a T degree
光の強さから光の弱さまで、T 度
This cell was originally in this place
この細胞はもともとこの場所にありました
It deliberately hit the body of this cell
意図的にこの細胞の体を叩いた
This cell will quickly escape to this place from here
この細胞はここからすぐにこの場所へ逃げます
Escape to that brightness where it can feel non-life threatening
命の危険がないと感じられる明るさに逃げましょう
it just stops
それはただ止まるだけです
So here is a T degree
これが T 学位です
There is a staircase-like intensity from high to low
高から低まで階段状の強度がある
After escaping to a certain intensity it can
一定の強度まで逃げた後は、
So from now on, we can know that light actually has a very, very, very, very, very, very very impact on life.
これから私たちは、光が実際に人生に非常に、非常に、非常に、非常に、非常に非常に大きな影響を与えていることを知ることができます。
There is also Chen Bizhang in our India Center
私たちのインドセンターにはチェン・ビジャンもいます。
Teacher Chen
チェン先生
Ms. Chen joined our center in July 2013
チェンさんは 2013 年 7 月に当センターに加わりました。
He specializes in this interesting work called
彼はこの興味深い仕事を専門としています。
3D movies of living cells or biological samples
生きた細胞や生体サンプルの 3D 動画
He said that he specialized in making this kind of film just like making a movie.
映画を作るのと同じように、この種の映画を作ることに特化していると彼は言いました。
that his
それは彼の
The male and female protagonists of the movie are all kinds of biological tissues
映画の主人公の男性と女性はあらゆる種類の生体組織です
when i made a movie
映画を作ったとき
especially in the microscope filming
特に顕微鏡撮影では
The hero and heroine must do something
ヒーローとヒロインは何かをしなければなりません
Just put some hot pepper on it to fix him
彼を治すには唐辛子を少しかけるだけです
just dead
ただ死んだだけ
can't move
動けない
I can't see clearly when I move
動くとよく見えない
then he is not
それなら彼はそうではない
He developed a new technique that is
彼は新しい技術を開発しました。
He can see anything
彼には何でも見えるよ
And can see more clearly than others
そして他の人よりもはっきりと見ることができます
alive again
再び生きています
Moreover, he can see images from all directions in real time.
さらに、あらゆる方向からの画像をリアルタイムで見ることができます。
the most important point
最も重要な点
That is to say, the image he saw
つまり、彼が見たイメージは、
yes
はい
this is a formula
これは公式です
formula engraved in stone
石に刻まれた公式
by Professor Abbe
アッベ教授による
Professor Abbe died in 1905
アッベ教授は1905年に亡くなった
He is an independent director of Zeiss AG
彼は Zeiss AG の独立取締役です。
Then he wrote down this formula
それから彼はこの式を書き留めました
that is
あれは
Recording is proportional to wavelength
記録は波長に比例します
Refractive index of the lens used
使用レンズの屈折率
inversely proportional to the dirty angle of the lens
レンズの汚れ角度に反比例します。
The Sci-C tower is inversely proportional to
Sci-Cタワーは反比例します
This means that the world knows
つまり世界は知っているということです
color limit
色の制限
This mainland China is called the limit of color rendering
この中国大陸は演色限界と呼ばれています
It is called Deflection Limit in English
英語ではDeflection Limitといいます。
That is to say, no matter how you look at it
つまりどう見ても
see things with an optical microscope
光学顕微鏡で物を見る
basically about half a wavelength of resolution
基本的に解像度の約半分の波長
This is what everyone knows
これは誰もが知っていることです
Our Professor Chen Mizhen
私たちの陳美珍教授
He can break through the limit like this
彼はこのように限界を突破することができます
Former Yongjian academician he won the Nobel Prize
元永建学者、ノーベル賞受賞
because of the use of fluorescent green protein
蛍光グリーンプロテインを使用しているため
fluorescent green protein
蛍光緑色タンパク質
It's about two nanometers wide
幅は約2ナノメートルです
Then three nanometers in length
すると長さは3ナノメートル
A fluorescent molecule like this
こんな蛍光分子
Another focused light spot, a focused light spot is about two to three hundred nanometers
もう一つの集束光スポット、集束光スポットは約 2 ～ 300 ナノメートルです
Then put a fluorescent molecule in such a small one, about 1/500th of it
500分の1くらいの小さな蛍光分子を入れます。
Then, if you look at the fluorescent image, this light spot is about 1/500th of the entire cell.
そこで蛍光像を見ると、この光点は細胞全体の約1/500です。
So use such a light spot to look at the fluorescent molecules in a cell
したがって、このような光のスポットを使用して、細胞内の蛍光分子を観察します
It can obtain very high-dimensional images, you can take a look
非常に高次元の画像が得られますので、ぜひご覧ください。
This is an image of live feed
これはライブフィードの画像です
If you can see the upper left, if your eyes are good enough
左上が見えていれば、目が良ければ
The purple in the upper left represents the nucleus
左上の紫は核を表します
Green represents the number of microtubules
緑色は微小管の数を表します
Red represents a stereo
赤はステレオを表します
it is the image of a cell
細胞のイメージです
Image of a fluorescent green protein called a cell
細胞と呼ばれる緑色蛍光タンパク質の画像
Using such technology
そういった技術を使って
for different proteins
さまざまなタンパク質に対応
Bottom is an image of a mouse neuron
下はマウスのニューロンの画像です
Both are dead fixed
どちらも完全に固定されています
Different colors represent different proteins
異なる色は異なるタンパク質を表します
you can see
見ることができます
It is very clear that such different representations
このような異なる表現があることは非常に明らかです
these states of protein
タンパク質のこれらの状態
Then you can see the cells
そうすれば細胞が見えるよ
Cellular organelles that can be seen inside the cell
細胞内の細胞小器官が見える
You can also see protein
プロテインも見れます
You can also see the real-time video like this
このようなリアルタイムビデオも見ることができます
Just ask me what he thinks
彼がどう思っているか聞いてください
of course he's amazing
もちろん彼は素晴らしいです
he invented a technique
彼は技術を発明した
This technology is the same as in 2014
この技術は2014年と同じです
Technology developed with Professor Eric Bezit, Nobel Prize in Chemistry
ノーベル化学賞エリック・ベジット教授と開発した技術
This technique is the general optical microscope is like this
この手法は一般的な光学顕微鏡はこんな感じです
The objective lens of the microscope is focused on the sample
顕微鏡の対物レンズはサンプルに焦点を合わせます
What about after you look at it like this?
こうやって見てみたらどうでしょうか？
Because what you look at in front of you and behind you will interfere with you
前と後ろに見えるものが気になるから
like during the day, everyone
昼間のように、みんな
Can you see the stars in the sky? Can't you?
空に星が見えますか?見えませんか?
only at night
夜だけ
Because there is no such light pollution at night
夜はそんな光害がないから
Can you see the stars?
星が見えますか？
So the stars are always there
だから星はいつもそこにある
just remove the background
背景を削除するだけです
So this background will affect you
この背景があなたに影響を与えるでしょう
So generally speaking, use confoco
したがって、一般的に言えば、confoco を使用します
Confoco focuses the light spot to a very small point
Confoco は光点を非常に小さな点に集中させます
or to photo, multi-photo
または写真、マルチ写真
look at this sample
このサンプルを見てください
Then swipe this sample
次に、このサンプルをスワイプします
about ten years ago
10年ほど前
they developed a technique
彼らは技術を開発した
That is to say, I don't want to use this light
つまり、このライトは使いたくないのです
I light from the side
横から照らします
If you have this experience
こんな経験をお持ちの方なら
Walk into a room and see a light count down
部屋に入ると、ライトのカウントダウンが表示されます
it's full of dust
埃だらけだ
That's because you're here to light
それはあなたが光を当てるためにここにいるからです
your eyes can see
あなたの目で見ることができます
Otherwise, how can you usually see the dust?
そうでなければ、通常どうやって塵を見ることができるのでしょうか？
then this is the concept
それならこれがコンセプトです
It's just a ray of light
それはただの光線だ
you are in this area of ​​no light
あなたは光のないこの領域にいます
Look at the effect of light and matter
光と物質の効果を見てください
So this can see a lot
これでたくさんのことがわかります
flash some images
いくつかの画像をフラッシュする
that flashing image
その点滅するイメージ
you can put very small things
非常に小さなものを置くことができます
can show
見せることができる
that goes further
それはさらに進みます
they were in previous years
彼らは前年にいた
how about a light like this
こんなライトはどうでしょうか
so-called back handle
いわゆるバックハンドル
Then you will ask me what is a back handle
次に、バックハンドルとは何ですかと尋ねるでしょう
Reciprocal square is a fraction of mathematics
逆二乗は数学の分数です
What about the production of the back handle?
バックハンドルの製作はどうなりますか？
It is the tail of this object
この物体の尻尾です
Raiwei it puts the light in the light
ライウェイ それは光の中に光を置きます
just become a circle
ただ円になるだけ
a ring light
リングライト
After typing in
入力後
The ring light will focus
リングライトの焦点が合います
Interfering with each other after focusing
合焦後の相互干渉
interfere with each other
互いに干渉し合う
some interference fringes
いくつかの干渉縞
You can see it in the next picture
次の写真でわかります
It shoots light in, and it shoots light in with two object paths
光を射込み、2 つのオブジェクト パスで光を射込みます
One is light coming in, after the light comes in, the light will interfere with each other
1つは光が入ってくること、光が入った後、光は互いに干渉します
As far as two lights are concerned, after interference, interference fringes will be produced one by one.
2本の光線が干渉すると、次々と干渉縞が生じます
This is the interference fringe, this puts some dye in it
これが干渉縞です、これに染料を入れます
You can see these interference fringes one by one
この干渉縞を一本一本見ることができます
Then these interference fringes are the same as the focus just now
すると、この干渉縞が先ほどの焦点と同じになります。
Gather to a minimum thickness of about 500 microns
最小約500ミクロンの厚さに集めます
This is about 0.5micron thick
厚さは約0.5ミクロンです
Sorry for my mistake, this is about 5micron in thickness
すみません、私の間違いです、これは厚さ約5ミクロンです
This is the thickness of 0.5micron, one-tenth of the thickness
これは、従来の10分の1の0.5ミクロンの厚さです。
so it can look thin
だから細く見えるかも
Then do a tomographic scan, just like this
次に、このように断層撮影スキャンを実行します
A living one like this, this is a living IC package
こんな生きたもの、これが生きたICパッケージ
it just sweeps over
それはただ通り過ぎていくだけ
We went to see the video, he recorded it
私たちはビデオを見に行き、彼はそれを録画しました
After recording it, he reconstructed it from measurements
録音後、測定結果から再構築した
Different directions to rebuild, like this
再構築のさまざまな方向性、このように
Here's the actual architecture of his experiment
これが彼の実験の実際のアーキテクチャです
Two object paths, actually there are three object paths here
2 つのオブジェクト パス、実際にはここには 3 つのオブジェクト パスがあります
There are actually
実際には、
As you can see, this is a
ご覧のとおり、これは
cancer cell
癌細胞
It's a real-time motion image, a fluorescent image
リアルタイム動画、蛍光画像です
the background looks very dark
背景がとても暗く見える
so it looks very clear
とてもはっきりと見えます
The contrast is very good
コントラストがとても良いです
images like this
このような画像
he did a lot
彼はたくさんのことをした
I can't report to everyone one by one.
いちいち全員に報告することはできません。
Because it involves a lot of research
多くの研究が必要なため
basic biology, and some
基本的な生物学といくつかの
pharmacology, and some other reactions
薬理学、およびその他の反応
Then I have selected a few to compare
次に、比較するためにいくつかを選択しました
simple
単純
You can see this at the bottom left
左下にこれが表示されます
The first one is an image of the nucleus
1枚目は核の画像です
The second is the image of this solid
2枚目はこの立体の画像です
It is the image of generating ATP to generate energy
ATPを生成してエネルギーを生み出すイメージです
This is the same cell
これは同じ細胞です
And this is the image of the inner fat network
これが内部ファットネットワークの画像です
That is, it can distinguish between different proteins
つまり、異なるタンパク質を区別できるということです。
Individual images can then be extracted
個々の画像を抽出できます
and put it together like this
そしてこのように組み立てます
Then it places different slices at different depths
次に、異なるスライスを異なる深さに配置します。
it can see its
それはそれを見ることができます
instant dynamic response
瞬時の動的応答
different location
別の場所
So put it all together and you can see the change of its overall image
すべてをまとめると、全体のイメージが変化することがわかります
this is
これは
one depends on the present
人は現在に依存している
very important
とても重要な
The development of optical technology
光学技術の発展
And computer big data processing
そしてコンピューターによるビッグデータ処理
And there is the image
そして画像があります
Some techniques for rebuilding
再構築のためのいくつかのテクニック
can see very important
非常に重要なことがわかります
This is a T cell
これはT細胞です
After he found a foreign cell
彼が異質な細胞を発見した後
he opened his mouth
彼は口を開いた
then swallow it
それからそれを飲み込みます
This is an image showing no foreign cells seen
これは外来細胞が見られないことを示す画像です
just see it
それを見てください
Then you can see the mouth open
すると口が開いているのがわかります
then he swallowed it
それから彼はそれを飲み込んだ
Some movies of some important some cells like this
いくつかの重要な細胞のいくつかの映画はこのようなものです
is his specialty
彼の専門です
This is just in the T cell
これはちょうど T 細胞内にあります
when you want to open your mouth to swallow it
口を開けて飲み込みたいとき
When he opens his mouth, some acidic substances will be produced
口を開けると酸性物質が発生します
then lyse the cells
次に細胞を溶解します
swallow it up
それを飲み込む
This word is the same cell
この単語は同じ細胞です
look at it from different directions
さまざまな方向から見てください
So you can see that this cell divides in the middle
この細胞が真ん中で分裂しているのがわかります
Then split successfully
その後、分割に成功しました
and then become two different individuals
そして二人の異なる人間になる
That
それか
This is a kind of Hila-Sel, which is the kind of cancer cells of uterine well cancer
これは子宮癌の癌細胞の一種であるヒラセルの一種です。
It has no way to successfully split in the process of splitting, entangled together
分裂の過程でうまく分裂するわけがなく、絡み合ってしまう
That is, the cells have no ability to regenerate.
つまり、細胞には再生能力がありません。
That is, after it is treated with drugs, it will not regenerate, it will only wither
つまり、薬で治療した後は再生せず、枯れるだけです。
So some images like this can be seen by it
したがって、このようないくつかの画像が表示されます
that's a fruit camp one...sorry, it's a live insect egg
それはフルーツキャンプのものです...ごめんなさい、生きた昆虫の卵です
This is the egg of a living insect, the green one you see now is its chromosome
これは生きている昆虫の卵です、今見えている緑色のものはその染色体です
it is undergoing nuclear division of this cell
この細胞は核分裂中です
So the following is the fruit camp
ということで以下はフルーツキャンプです
This is the egg of the fruit camp
フルーツキャンプの卵です
Sure enough, the soft cell membrane
案の定、柔らかい細胞膜
you can see
見ることができます
it's been squeezing each other
お互いに圧迫し合っている
How does its extruding cells extrude and harden?
押し出された細胞はどのようにして押し出され、硬化するのでしょうか?
In fact it has always been a puzzle
実際、それは常にパズルだった
How do these mechanical effects arise
このような機械的効果はどのようにして生じるのでしょうか
In fact it is not clear
実際のところは明らかではない
This is the first time you can see so clearly
こんなにはっきり見えるのは初めてです
A change like this on its cell membrane
細胞膜の上部にはこのような変化が
This is the heart of a zebrafish three-day-old baby zebrafish
これはゼブラフィッシュの生後3日目の赤ちゃんゼブラフィッシュの心臓です
The heart of this zebrafish
このゼブラフィッシュの心臓
You can see that is to say
つまり、
about this size
このくらいのサイズ
About 50 to 100micron heart
約50～100ミクロンの心臓
Then it also moves with the cardiomyocytes
そして心筋細胞と一緒に動きます
The orange part represents the nucleus
オレンジ色の部分が核を表します
The green part is the cytoplasm
緑色の部分は細胞質です
So you can clearly see
それではっきりとわかります
entire
全体
From cell to heart
細胞から心臓へ
and then what else
それから他に何か
This is a mouse brain neuron
これはマウスの脳のニューロンです
this is the nucleus
これが核です
Then this branch is the nerve cell's
そして、この枝は神経細胞の枝です
one by one nerve
神経の一つ一つ
Then he can see clearly
そうすれば彼ははっきりと見えるようになります
Of course this is processed
もちろん加工済みです
After transparent processing
透明加工後
This is before processing, this is after processing
こちらが加工前、こちらが加工後
Then you can see the brain cells go deep inside some of the
すると、脳細胞がいくつかの部分に深く入っていくのがわかります。
The last one you can see is
最後に見えるのは、
his technique
他的技術
Fluorescence Microscopy
蛍光顕微鏡
so-called
いわゆる
Sad disease like this tomographic technique
この断層撮影技術のような悲しい病気
actually very very important
実はとてもとても重要
His Science of Paper last year
昨年の彼の紙の科学
Selected as one of the Science for a whole year
一年を通して科学の1つに選ばれました
most important articles
最も重要な記事
Then he gets Science
それから彼は科学を学びます
there is a very important
とても重要なことがあります
It's called the Newcombe Cleveland Award
ニューカム・クリーブランド賞と呼ばれるものです
This award has been around for more than eighty years
この賞は80年以上続いています
Eighty years ago it was Newcombe Cleveland
80年前、そこはニューコム・クリーブランドだった
Their family donated a sum of money
彼らの家族は多額の寄付をした
eighty years ago
80年前
His prize money is one thousand dollars
彼の賞金は1000ドルです
Eighty years ago, one thousand yuan was a lot
80年前、1000元は大金だった
So there was a
そこで、
Soulland dollars award
ソウルランドドル賞
is the highest award
最高賞です
It is the highest award of AAAS in the United States and Science magazine
米国AAASおよびサイエンス誌の最高賞である
So in February this year, during the Lunar New Year
さて、今年の2月、旧正月の時期に
Everyone celebrates the New Year here and he flew to New York to receive the award
みんながここで新年を祝い、彼は賞を受け取るためにニューヨークへ飛んだ
We had a lot of bad news in the hospital
病院では悪い知らせがたくさんありました
So the good news was never reported.
そのため、良い知らせは決して報道されませんでした。
OK good
いいよ
The remaining time is now eight nineteen
残り時間は8時19分です
not much time left
残り時間はあまりない
Then I will report to you
それではご報告させていただきます
something else
何か他のもの
it's more interesting
それはもっと面白いです
In fact, there are many interesting things
実は面白いことがたくさんあるんです
I have limited time to share
共有できる時間が限られている
My personal knowledge is also limited
私の個人的な知識も限られています
So I thought I'd make some comparisons
そこで、いくつか比較してみようと思いました
interesting things i find
私が見つけた興味深いもの
Because a reporter came to me and asked me
記者が聞きに来たので
The invisibility cloak is not a dream
透明マントは夢じゃない
that Berkeley professor
あのバークレー教授
it was last september
去年の9月でした
Many major newspapers in Taiwan published it
台湾の多くの主要新聞がそれを掲載しました
say this
これ言ってみて
the most important thing is to say
最も重要なことは言うことです
Ask Zhang Xiang if this invisibility cloak is real
張祥にこの透明マントが本物か尋ねる
Professor Zhang Xiang said I can't see any obstacles
張祥教授は「障害物は見えない」と言いました
Many people came to me and asked
多くの人が私のところに来て尋ねました
Isn't that what you do?
それはあなたがやっていることではありませんか？
what is that obstacle
その障害は何ですか
why can't i see
なぜ見えないのか
this is a joke
これは冗談です
because of the invisibility cloak
透明マントのせいで
so can't see
だから見えない
This is actually a very important development
これは実際には非常に重要な開発です
How to tell this story?
この物語をどう伝えるか?
That is to say, Professor Zhang Qiang published this Size Paper last year
つまり、張強教授は昨年このサイズペーパーを出版しました
Then this Size Paper will tell you
このサイズペーパーが教えてくれます
Suppose you make some special artificial structures on a surface
表面上にいくつかの特別な人工構造を作成するとします。
These artificial structures allow incoming light
これらの人工構造物は光が入ってくることを可能にします
Follow your ideas to the direction you want him to go
彼に進んでほしい方向にあなたのアイデアに従ってください
that's all
それで全部です
So what if I make an invisibility cloak
じゃあ透明マント作ったらどうなるの？
It's easy for you to lose sight of me
あなたが私を見失ってしまうのは簡単です
I just let the light in
ただ光を入れただけです
Then run to the back
それから後ろに走ってください
you can't see me
あなたには私が見えない
Then the light went to the back and that's it
それから光が後ろに行って、それで終わりです
So what about his experiment?
では、彼の実験はどうでしょうか？
That is to say that on a surface with bumps and bumps
つまり、凹凸のある表面では
I went to lay out a lot of structures that are resistant to you
あなたに抵抗する構造物をたくさん配置しに行きました
make him look flat
彼を平坦に見せる
This is what his experiment looks like
これが彼の実験の様子です
So it turns out that this is where RO stands out
これがROの優れた点であることがわかりました
looks wrinkled
しわが寄っているように見える
but i'm up there now
でも私は今そこにいる
put some nanostructures
いくつかのナノ構造を入れる
it looks flat to me
私には平らに見えます
it is flat
平らです
that's it
それでおしまい
So this concept is very important
したがって、この概念は非常に重要です
So if you ask me
それで私に尋ねたら
There are various versions of this story
この物語にはさまざまなバージョンがあります
I won't talk much
あまり話さないよ
Size's cover is an invisibility cloak
サイズのカバーは透明マント
then very important
それからとても重要な
I still want to tell this story a little bit.
この話はまだ少しだけ語りたいと思います。
The story develops over a period of time
物語は時間をかけて展開していく
about 10 years
約10年
That is to say, 10 years ago, some people proposed that
つまり、10年前に何人かの人々が次のように提案しました。
Matter is made up of atoms and molecules
物質は原子と分子からできています
Assuming that humans can make artificial atoms and molecules
人間が人工の原子や分子を作れると仮定すると
to form a substance
物質を形成する
called
呼ばれた
Metal material, Metal means
金属素材、金属とは
Walking up means above, beyond
上に歩くということは、上を、超えてを意味します
So human technology
つまり人間のテクノロジー
Nanotechnology has developed to the present
ナノテクノロジーは現在まで発展しています
materials that can be made
作れる素材
Because artificial atoms have to have structure
人工原子には構造が必要なので
So these artificial atoms and the size of the molecule
つまり、これらの人工原子と分子の大きさは
Can't be as small as an atom
原子ほど小さくすることはできない
Because its most basic composition is the atomic molecule
最も基本的な構成は原子分子であるため、
Right, so it's always slightly bigger than an atomic molecule
そうですね、それは常に原子分子よりわずかに大きいです
But it must be more visible than us humans
でもそれは私たち人間よりも目に見えるはずです
The wavelength that can be seen like this comes from a small
こうやって見える波長は小さなものから来ている
to do something interesting
何か面白いことをするために
So a structure like this
ということで、こんな構造に
It affects physical properties that humans care about
人間が気にする物理的特性に影響を与える
Basically the two coefficients of electricity and magnetism
基本的に電気と磁気の 2 つの係数
The two coefficients of electricity and magnetism
電気と磁気の 2 つの係数
natural material
天然的材料
Its electric and magnetic coefficients are composed of atoms and molecules
その電気係数と磁気係数は原子と分子で構成されています
Influence
影響
The physical properties of electricity and magnetism in artificial structures
人工構造物における電気と磁気の物理的性質
are influenced by these artificial small structures
これらの人工的な小さな構造物の影響を受ける
To have an impact you have to put what comes in
インパクトを与えるには、入ってくるものを取り入れなければなりません
Changes in what is measured will have an impact
測定対象の変化は影響を与える
otherwise it won't work
そうしないと機能しません
right
右
So these things you have to go through a special design
したがって、これらのものは特別な設計を経る必要があります
So at that time, many people jumped in to do such an experiment.
それで当時、多くの人がそのような実験をしようと飛びつきました。
Including materials responsible for setting up
セットアップを担当する資料を含む
is everything before
それはすべて前のことです
This is how light goes
光はこうやって進む
Refractive index
屈折率
it goes the other way
それは違う方向に進みます
Then everyone used to walk on the right
昔はみんな右側を歩いてた
it keeps to the left
それは左側にあります
that anyway
それはともかく
something like it
それのようなもの
But later found a difficulty
しかし後で難点が見つかった
That is, if it's really efficient
つまり、それが本当に効率的であれば、
that comes in quickly
それはすぐに入る
If you want to have an effect with him, after it has an effect, the ones behind will have no effect with him.
あなたが彼に影響を与えたい場合、それが影響を及ぼした後、後ろの人は彼に影響を与えなくなります。
Because everything was done by his predecessor
すべては前任者がやったことだから
So after a few years, ten years
それで数年後、10年後
Started with some smart ones like
のようないくつかの賢いものから始めました
CAPASO, Professor, Department of Applied Physics, Harvard University
CAPASO、ハーバード大学応用物理学科教授
He said, let's not work so hard
彼は言った、「そんなに頑張らないようにしよう」
Because making that Metameteria requires artificial atoms and artificial molecules
そのメタメテリアを作るには人工原子と人工分子が必要だから
To do it well, one by one, to do it well for many years
一つ一つ丁寧にやる事、何年もしっかりやる事
So we just make a thin layer
だから、薄い層を作るだけです
Anyway, only the first few layers work.
とにかく、最初の数層だけが機能します。
So it's called Metameteria Surface
だからそれはメタメテリアサーフェスと呼ばれます
We focus on Metameteria Surface
メタメテリア表面に焦点を当てます
Metameteria Surface as long as the efficiency is good enough
効率が十分であればメタメテリアサーフェス
Soon you can complete the artificial substance you want
もうすぐあなたが望む人工物質が完成します
So he proposed to use this V-shaped
そこで彼は、この V 字型を使用することを提案しました。
Nanostructures of something like a boomerang
ブーメランのようなもののナノ構造
To control the electromagnetic wave or light that enters the color
色に入る電磁波や光をコントロールするには
It hits this entry above each dot
各ドットの上にこのエントリがヒットします
After it interacts with it, it will produce different items
相互作用するとすぐに、さまざまなアイテムが生成されます
ok, i'm sorry, there's no way to not give the formula at all
わかりました、ごめんなさい、式をまったく与えない方法はありません
So let me talk about
それで話させてください
When you were in junior high school, you learned that entering the character role is equal to the anti-role role
キャラ役に入る＝アンチ役になるって中学生の時に習ったよね
Snees Law, Snees Law
スニーズ法、スニーズ法
N1, Sci-Ct-1 is equal to N2, Sci-Ct-2
N1、Sci-Ct-1 は N2、Sci-Ct-2 に等しい
So look at the fish in the water in the air
だから空中の水の中の魚を見てください
The position of the fish will be different from its real position
魚の位置が実際の位置と異なります
Because of the folding angle
折り曲げ角度のせいで
Because water has a different refractive index than air, right?
だって、水は空気とは屈折率が違うんですよね？
that description is correct
その説明は正しいです
But that water has to be pretty flat
でもその水はかなり平らでなければなりません
If the water surface is uneven, if the interface is uneven
水面に凹凸がある場合、界面に凹凸がある場合
is a structured word
構造化された単語です
It is necessary to put the contribution of this structure in
私たちはこの構造の貢献を次のことに投入しなければなりません
so without it
だからそれなしで
So capasso wrote the so-called generized snare's law
そこでカパッソはいわゆる生成されたスネアの法則を書きました
Generalized, extensive snare's law
一般化された広範なスネアの法則
That is to say, one more contribution is the contribution generated by the surface
つまり、もう 1 つの寄与は表面によって生成される寄与です。
There is one more item from reflection or refraction.
反射または屈折からもう 1 つの項目があります。
This is one more item, he won the highest award of the International Society for Conceptual Engineering
こちらはもう一つ、国際概念工学学会の最高賞を受賞しました。
The Optical Society of America's highest award
アメリカ光学協会の最高賞
And iQIPOE's highest award
そしてiQIPOEの最高賞
It's because of this extra item
この余計なアイテムのせいで
so very important
とても重要です
Ask me if it's simple, very simple
シンプルかどうか聞いてください、とてもシンプルです
but he just wrote it out
でも彼はただそれを書き出しただけだ
With this concept
このコンセプトで
Many people do related research
多くの人が関連する研究を行っています
We also did some research
私たちもいくつか調査しました
What we do is the so-called full photo
私たちがやっているのはいわゆるフル写真です
General full photo like your credit card
クレジットカードなどの一般的な全身写真
Or those full photos that you see at art museums
あるいは美術館で見るような全身写真
We are in every pixel of every full photo
私たちはすべての写真のすべてのピクセルの中にいます
This is a single pixel
これは単一ピクセルです
Put different nanostructures inside
内部に異なるナノ構造を入れる
the nanostructure
ナノ構造
One is NTU, the other is RCAAS
1 つは NTU、もう 1 つは RCAAS
Then it goes in a different direction
そうするとまた違う方向に行ってしまいます
If the direction is different
方向が違うと
The images you get in and out with different polarized light are different.
偏光が違うと入ってくる映像と出てくる映像が違います。
then you ask me
それからあなたは私に尋ねます
what's the fun in that
それの何が楽しいのですか
that is to tell you
それはあなたに伝えることです
In fact, the previous polarized full photo
実は、以前の偏光した全体写真
Only one image can be projected
投影できる画像は 1 つだけです
There is no biased information in that image.
その画像には偏った情報は含まれていません。
We can now be inside a pixel
ピクセルの中に入ることができるようになりました
also contains biased messages
偏ったメッセージも含まれています
That is to say, the original image
つまり元の画像
it is intensity
それは激しさです
also in different colors
色違いでも
There are different information
違う情報もある
So we now add one more dimension
そこで、もう 1 つの次元を追加します
It is an additional dimension of information
それは情報のさらなる次元です
Then you ask me, can I add more?
それから、もっと追加してもいいですか？と尋ねます。
sure
もちろん
if you have the ability
あなたに能力があるなら
It will change from three-dimensional to four-dimensional to five-dimensional to multi-dimensional
三次元から四次元、五次元、多次元へと変化していきます。
Multidimensional information is placed in a Single Pixel
多次元の情報を単一のピクセルに配置
As long as you can design some nanostructures like this
このようなナノ構造を設計できる限り、
so you can control
あなたがコントロールできるように
Is it projected to be NTU or projected to be RCA
NTUになると予測されますか、それともRCAになると予測されますか
It can also project on both sides simultaneously
両面同時投影も可能
It has something to do with the polarized direction of your colored light
それは色の光の偏光方向と関係があります
that this is very interesting stuff
これはとても興味深いものです
Then after we develop these things
これらを開発した後、
That's because it's targeting a wavelength
それは波長を狙っているからです
Later we also developed RGB
その後RGBも開発しました
Different wavelengths are broadband
さまざまな波長がブロードバンドです
Full Spectrum Different Colors
フルスペクトルのさまざまな色
All can be applied to a full photo of a nanometer like this
このようにナノメートルの全体写真にすべて適用できます
Then this is the result of it
そしたらその結果がこれです
Then you ask me, what is the use of having these things?
それでは、これらのものを持っていて何の役に立つのかと尋ねます。
Of course useful
もちろん便利です
You may not know
あなたは知らないかもしれません
about fifty or sixty years ago
50年か60年ほど前
After the Second and Fourth Four Seasons War
第二次・第四次四季戦争後
A very famous large pharmaceutical company in Europe
ヨーロッパでは非常に有名な大手製薬会社
when it is making a medicine
薬を作っているとき
Everyone knows that medicine is
薬というものは誰もが知っています
After knowing that a certain molecule is useful
ある分子が役に立つことがわかった後
just synthesize it
それを合成するだけ
But during the synthesis
しかし合成の途中で
that molecular weight is the same
分子量が同じであるということ
but it is mirrored
しかしそれは鏡映されています
its two mirror images
二つの鏡像
Those two mirror images are just right
この二つの鏡像はちょうどいい
this left hand
この左手
this kind
この種
Right hand
右手
open me
私を開いてください
This one is Left hand
こちらは左手用です
one is sorry
一つはごめんなさい
One is Right hand
一つは右手です
One is Left hand
一人は左手です
Then what
じゃあ何
Just right for its medicinal properties
薬効にぴったり
Chemical properties are different
化学的性質が違う
so what
だから何
There are many of these
これらはたくさんあります
After the sick woman took the medicine
病気の女性が薬を飲んだ後
Babies born without hands
手を持たずに生まれた赤ちゃん
no hands
手がありません
Well, this matter was actually not settled until the lawsuit was settled three years ago.
実はこの問題は3年前の訴訟まで決着がついていなかった
A total of nearly 5 million pounds of this money was paid to these victims
このうち総額500万ポンド近くが被害者に支払われた
and the victims who are still alive
そして今も生きている被害者たち
What about the drug Salidome?
それからサリドームという薬
This drug was actually a very important drug in the past
実はこの薬、昔はとても重要な薬だったのです
That is because in the process of treatment
それは治療の過程で
Neglected that the medicinal properties of the left hand and the right hand are different
左手と右手の薬効が異なることを無視
Hence the aftermath
したがって余波は
Then you ask me how do you detect the left hand and right hand
次に、左手と右手をどうやって検出するのかと尋ねます。
that's really troublesome
それは本当に面倒だ
Your change means that you want to synthesize this medicine after
あなたの変更は、この薬を次の後に合成したいことを意味します
to separate it
それを分けるために
how do you detect
どのように検出しますか
Even if you take it apart today
今日分解しても
do you worry
心配しますか
Then you will say that I will melt it in the water
そしたら水に溶かしてやるって言うだろう
and then use
そして使用します
This different left-handed off right-handed off to hit it
この違う左打ち右打ちオフ
Then look out the result
それから結果を見てください
But the results you see need a lot of molecules to have an effect
しかし、あなたが見ている結果には効果をもたらすために多くの分子が必要です
So is there any way to detect instantly
それで、すぐに検出する方法はありますか
Left Hand circular police and Y hand circular police came out
左手円形警察とY字円形警察が出てきました
You can go to different points by typing it out
入力すると別のポイントに移動できます
Because we use Laimi's technology
ライミの技術を使用しているため
So we can have a very small range
したがって、非常に小さな範囲を設定できます
We can do something like this with very little
非常に少ないお金でこのようなことができます
So we can do a very efficient
したがって、非常に効率的な作業が可能です
and very fast filtering
非常に高速なフィルタリング
Just to do a meta analyzer like this
このようなメタアナライザーを実行するだけです
It is the use of this meta surface technology to do the meta analyzer just mentioned
このメタ サーフェス テクノロジーを使用して、先ほど述べたメタ アナライザーを実行します。
This article was recently accepted for publication
この記事は最近出版が受理されました
So with this structure of Laimi in different directions
ライミのこの構造をさまざまな方向に
Different bias control
異なるバイアス制御
Polarized in a different direction, since it is found that it will project onto this point
この点に投影されることが判明したため、別の方向に偏光します。
or projected to this point, depending on its polarization
または、偏光に応じてこの点に投影されます
Then its polarization is after interacting with this substance
そして、その分極はこの物質と相互作用した後です
what does its polarization look like
その偏光はどのようなものですか
ok, then this me
はい、ではこれが私です
What about our students, so
私たちの生徒たちはどうでしょうか？
Just taught by Carposo
カルポーゾに教わったばかり
Project Maxima, recruited to his laboratory
プロジェクト・マキシマ、研究室に採用される
Then he is in this year's
それから彼は今年の
June 3 cover
6月3日の表紙
Just made a Metal Lens
メタルレンズを作りました
that is a lens
それはレンズです
Because all photos are very complicated, an image needs to be projected
すべての写真は非常に複雑なので、画像を投影する必要があります
Then when he went, he said, what are you doing?
それから彼が行ったとき、彼は言いました、「何をしているのですか？」
Do Metal Hologram
メタルホログラムをやる
You say Metal Hologram, don't bother
メタルホログラムって言うけど、気にしないでね
Just project on a point
点に投影するだけ
So before projecting as an image
画像として投影する前に
Projected at a point, it is called Metal Lens
点で投影されるものをメタルレンズと呼びます
So now this student is called Chen Weiting
さて、この学生はチェン・ウェイティンと呼ばれるようになりました
he did very well
彼はとてもよくやった
Then this year he published an article
そして今年、彼は記事を発表しました
Size Fondant, called Metal Lens
メタルレンズと呼ばれるフォンダンサイズ
Then, take the H of Harvard
次に、ハーバード大学の H を取得します。
see clearly
はっきり見える
And now he is helping Apple, Google and the three sacred companies every day
そして今、彼は毎日 Apple、Google、そして 3 つの神聖な企業を支援しています。
Because they all signed him up to buy the technology
なぜなら、彼らは皆、テクノロジーを購入するために彼にサインアップしたからです
To replace what? To replace the lens of this phone
何を交換しますか? この携帯電話のレンズを交換します
So the last few slides
最後の数枚のスライドは
That is to say, from the past, human beings invented
つまり、昔から人間が発明してきたのです。
Various nanostructures
さまざまなナノ構造
then through conversion optics
次に変換光学を介して
Can make this raised thing look like it's not raised
この隆起したものを隆起していないように見せることができます
just pretending to be flat
ただ平らなふりをしているだけ
Then you can make adjustments
その後、調整できます
convertible
コンバーチブル
To the so-called Meta Device
いわゆるメタデバイスへ
That is, many devices or components in the future
つまり、将来の多くのデバイスやコンポーネント
Just use it directly, it is done in this nano way
直接使用するだけです。このナノ方法で行われます。
will be
になるだろう
We consider a very important development in optics
私たちは光学分野の非常に重要な発展を考慮しています
The reason is because optics is a science that controls the path of light
その理由は、光学は光の経路を制御する科学だからです。
Or a study of the interaction between light and matter
または光と物質の間の相互作用の研究
Finally, I want to show you a video
最後に動画をご紹介したいと思います
Because many reporters asked me
多くの記者が私に尋ねたので、
How do you feel about what Professor Zhang made?
張教授が作ったものについてどう思いますか?
I dare not speak because I respect Professor Zhang very much
張先生をとても尊敬しているのであえて話さない
He is the chairman of our middle academic information committee
彼は私たちの中学術情報委員会の委員長です
I worked for three years
3年間働きました
Then I thought of a solution
それから解決策を考えました
I found this slide
このスライドを見つけました
This slideshow is made by me
このスライドショーは私が作成したものです
I went out of my way to find this movie
わざわざこの映画を探しに行きました
use your skin to change color and texture.
肌を使って色や質感を変えます。
There's some algae in the foreground and an octopus.
手前に藻とタコがいます。
Isn't that amazing?
それはすごいことではないでしょうか？
Now Roger spooked him so he took off with a cloud of ink,
ロジャーが彼を怖がらせたので、彼はインクの雲を抱えて飛び去った。
lands, and when he lands the octopus says,
着陸すると、タコはこう言います。
I've been seen best thing to do is get as big as I can get.
できる限り大きくなることが最善の策だと私は見てきました。
That big brown makes his eye spot very big.
その大きな茶色は彼の目の斑点をとても大きくしています。
So he's bluffing, let's do it backwards.
つまり、彼はハッタリを掛けているのです。逆にやりましょう。
I thought he was joking when he first showed it,
最初に見せたときは冗談かと思ったが、
I thought it was all graphics.
全部グラフィックだと思ってた。
So here it is in reverse.
ということで、ここでは逆になります。
Watch the skin color, watch the skin texture,
肌の色を観察し、肌の質感を観察し、
just an amazing animal can change color and texture
驚くべき動物だけが色や質感を変えることができます
to match the surroundings.
周囲に合わせて。
Watch them blend right into this algae.
それらがこの藻類に溶け込む様子を観察してください。
One, two, three.
1 2 3。
Now he's gone and so am I.
今、彼は去り、私も去ってしまいました。
Pattern, color, whiteness, and texture.
柄、色、白さ、質感。
Actually I have many, many videos
実はたくさんの動画を持っています
I just choose one
私はただ一つを選ぶだけです
That Zhang Yu, you dropped him out of the sea
あの張宇、あなたは彼を海から落としました
As soon as he arrives at the fake version, his eyes will see the color of your fake version
彼が偽バージョンに到着するとすぐに、彼の目にはあなたの偽バージョンの色が見えるでしょう
His color is exactly the same as the counterfeit color
彼の色は偽物の色と全く同じです
change in seconds
数秒で変わる
he changes the color
彼は色を変える
how does that color change
その色はどう変わるのですか
Did you say pigment? Not quite
色素って言いましたか? 違うんです
including his wrinkles
彼のシワも含めて
including the structures above the skin
皮膚の上の構造を含む
his eyes are ring shaped
彼の目はリング状です
his circular vision
彼の円形のビジョン
After taking the photo, he will fully blend in with the situation around him.
写真を撮った後、彼は周囲の状況に完全に溶け込みます。
So I can tell you about this
それで、これについてお話しできます
In fact, this world already has such
実際、この世界にはすでにそのようなものがあります
tunable, adjustable
調整可能な、調整可能な
reconfigurable, reconfigurable
再構成可能な、再構成可能な
Some creatures like this exist
こういう生き物もいるのね
Then why can't there be man-made
ではなぜ人工的に作れないのか
Such a structure exists
そういう構造があるんですね
Sure, just say how much it will cost you
はい、いくらかかるか言ってください
So I answered the reporter and said
そこで私は記者にこう答えました。
An invisibility cloak I know I'm hard at work 100micron by 100micron
透明マント、私は一生懸命働いているのはわかっている 100ミクロン×100ミクロン
An invisibility cloak, say 1 meter by 1 meter
透明マント、たとえば1メートル×1メートル
It might take me 1000 times the paper to finish
読み終わるまでに紙の1000倍かかるかもしれない
With current time and technology
今の時代とテクノロジーで
But you said it's possible, of course it's possible
でもあなたはそれが可能だと言いました、もちろん可能です
The world's most famous Southampton UK
世界で最も有名な英国サウサンプトン
The University of Southampton is the most famous school in optoelectronics in the world
サウサンプトン大学はオプトエレクトロニクス分野で世界で最も有名な学校です
They published the so-called Tunable
彼らはいわゆる Tunable を公開しました。
Some structures like this have been published
このような構造物がいくつか公開されています
And there is Professor Hedge in Germany
そしてドイツにはヘッジ教授がいます
They have also developed a variety of mechanical or electronically controlled
彼らはまた、機械的または電子的に制御されるさまざまなシステムも開発しました。
or thermodynamic heat induction
または熱力学的熱誘導
Our laboratory has also done some
私たちの研究室でもいくつかのことを行いました
People are doing Pingtang
人々は平塘をやっています
The area of ​​Pingtang is very high
屏塘の面積は非常に高いです